<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2024-10-02T01:32:02+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/feed.xml</id><author><name>PDIS</name></author><entry><title type="html">See how new technology can be grounded from the perspective of dispatch orders</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%BE%9E%E6%B4%BE%E8%BB%8A%E5%96%AE%E7%9C%8B%E6%96%B0%E7%A7%91%E6%8A%80%E5%A6%82%E4%BD%95%E6%8E%A5%E5%9C%B0%E6%B0%A3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="See how new technology can be grounded from the perspective of dispatch orders" /><published>2024-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%BE%9E%E6%B4%BE%E8%BB%8A%E5%96%AE%E7%9C%8B%E6%96%B0%E7%A7%91%E6%8A%80%E5%A6%82%E4%BD%95%E6%8E%A5%E5%9C%B0%E6%B0%A3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%BE%9E%E6%B4%BE%E8%BB%8A%E5%96%AE%E7%9C%8B%E6%96%B0%E7%A7%91%E6%8A%80%E5%A6%82%E4%BD%95%E6%8E%A5%E5%9C%B0%E6%B0%A3/"><![CDATA[<p>The Dispatch Form is a document required when using government vehicles. Despite its small size, it contains numerous fields, from the applicant’s name and purpose of use to the driver’s entries of travel time, mileage, fuel consumption, and more—amounting to dozens of details. Once completed, the form is submitted to the management unit and entered into the system for future reference.</p>

<p>With digitalization, this administrative process moved online, saving time from manual data entry. However, this shift poses a challenge for drivers not accustomed to mobile input.</p>

<p>This transition from paper to digital often presents a common issue: solving a problem for one group while creating a burden for another. When both sides have a voice, how should this be managed?</p>

<p>Department heads typically gather frontline experiences through focus interviews or an employee suggestion box. Despite the effort of reviewing each response, finding a solution that satisfies both parties is challenging.</p>

<p>Let’s hear what everyone has to say!</p>

<p>The Ministry of Digital Affairs utilizes an internal democratic system called “my moda.” Nearly six hundred colleagues can propose innovative solutions or address current policy challenges through this platform. If a proposal receives thirty likes within ten working days on the discussion platform, it is forwarded to the relevant unit for feasibility studies. After refining the proposal, it is presented to all colleagues for a vote.</p>

<p>If the proposal garners one hundred votes within five working days, it will be discussed further during the monthly ministerial livestream. Participants can ask questions anonymously online. Only after gaining consensus is the proposal adopted.</p>

<p>During digital transformation, our biggest concern is not understanding the actual needs, and a top-down approach often fails to solve problems, creating new ones instead. However, if we know that more than one-sixth of our colleagues share a common need, we can address the majority’s issues more effectively.
Returning to the dispatch form example, users commonly seek convenience, though their solutions differ. On the discussion platform and in livestreams, everyone can voice their opinions, evaluating new foundations to balance diverse interests.</p>

<p>The final decision was to implement OCR (Optical Character Recognition) technology, allowing drivers to continue handwriting. For drivers, writing a few words is faster than photographing the odometer and uploading the numbers. The subsequent processing is fully digitized, utilizing generative AI to automatically extract fields from the handwritten forms, eliminating the need for manual entry.</p>

<p>By digitizing these dispatch forms, statistical analysis can generate more innovative proposals. For example, if the most frequent reason for dispatch is to deliver confidential documents, we can further explore end-to-end encryption and fully implement online signing to save more time.</p>

<p>Through our internal democratic mechanism, the integration between users and new technology smoothens, even giving basic dispatch forms new value.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Hsin-Ting Fang</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Digital Strategy" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Ministry of Digital Affairs utilizes an internal democratic system called "my moda." Nearly six hundred colleagues can propose innovative solutions or address current policy challenges through this platform.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/mymoda.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/mymoda.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">AI’s Path to Becoming Humanlike</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/AI-%E7%9A%84%E6%88%90-%E4%BA%BA-%E4%B9%8B%E8%B7%AF/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AI’s Path to Becoming Humanlike" /><published>2024-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/AI-%E7%9A%84%E6%88%90%E3%80%8C%E4%BA%BA%E3%80%8D%E4%B9%8B%E8%B7%AF</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/AI-%E7%9A%84%E6%88%90-%E4%BA%BA-%E4%B9%8B%E8%B7%AF/"><![CDATA[<p>The allure and concern surrounding generative AI stem from its increasing resemblance to human beings.</p>

<p>For instance, by using just a few photographs, AI can synthesize a human face that appears flawless from every angle.</p>

<p>Similarly, with a mere 15 seconds of recorded speech, AI can capture a voice model and convincingly mimic the speaker’s tone, potentially deceiving even close friends and family.</p>

<p>Beyond appearance and voice, AI can also imitate human behavior online.</p>

<p>It can learn from the places a person likes or frequently comments on. Websites and apps can simulate user preferences based solely on the duration of attention spent on a particular page, without requiring active typing or photo uploads.</p>

<p>An AI model trained in this manner, with minor variations, can transform into thousands or millions of distinct “virtual individuals” in the online world. For example, beneath a viral article, there might be thousands of seemingly lively comments, but in reality, they could be generated by the same AI system using different personas to create specific emotions or even intensify polarization.</p>

<p>These comments differ from the obviously fake, templated messages of the past. With generative AI, each account may feature a unique profile picture, friends, check-ins, photos, and possess a lifelike history. When a manipulation attack launches, they can swarm to a specific location and leave comments.</p>

<p>To better integrate these “virtual individuals” into the human world, genuine human intervention is still required for “alignment tuning.” Much like teaching children, it involves guiding AI on which responses are more acceptable and which are not, enabling AI reactions to more closely resemble those of humans.</p>

<p>Realistic AI is a powerful tool for fraud, yet simultaneously serves as an excellent assistant for productivity and creativity. The tool remains the same; its behavior, whether virtuous or malicious, depends on the user.</p>

<p>In my “Superalignment” column late last year, I mentioned the open-source automatic alignment technology “Constitutional AI.” By allowing groups to write guiding principles on “how AI should better respond,” AI can adapt to the varying preferences of people with different attributes and cultures, akin to the diverse customs and perceptions among different nations.</p>

<p>For example, in the news industry, AI would be expected to prioritize the veracity of sources. If insufficient evidence exists, it would preferably admit ignorance rather than provide a fabricated answer.</p>

<p>Conversely, a group of science fiction writers might have the opposite requirement, encouraging AI to be as creative as possible, even if it means conjuring up stories, as long as they are captivating.</p>

<p>Thus, AI systems trained under these two different “constitutions” would react in entirely different ways. No single AI system can be universally applicable. Only through alignment tuning can AI systems become more attuned to users and interact in a more “human-like” manner.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Hsin-Ting Fang</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Digital Industries" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Realistic AI is a powerful tool for fraud, yet simultaneously serves as an excellent assistant for productivity and creativity.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/piano-7303732_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/piano-7303732_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">AI against AI</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E4%BB%A5-AI-%E6%B2%BB-AI/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AI against AI" /><published>2024-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E4%BB%A5-AI-%E6%B2%BB-AI</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E4%BB%A5-AI-%E6%B2%BB-AI/"><![CDATA[<p>In the past, single-page scam e-commerce websites proliferated, yet in 2022, fewer than 3,000 such sites were taken down. Following the establishment of the Ministry of Digital Affairs, the number of such sites blocked in 2023 surged to over 30,000, averaging nearly 100 daily.</p>

<p>Traditionally, organized fraudsters utilized live calls for one-on-one scams, potentially requiring training to mimic celebrities. However, the maturation of AI technology has significantly “empowered” fraudulent activities.</p>

<p>With the advent of deepfake technology two years ago, I proactively sought to inoculate the public by commissioning a deepfake video of myself, utilizing an actor. Due to our facial similarities, without explicit clarification, viewers might simply presume Audrey Tang had altered her appearance, oblivious to the impersonation.</p>

<p>This video’s creation demanded neither sophisticated equipment nor exorbitant costs, employing readily accessible technology. A laptop and twelve hours suffice for completion, hardly constituting a major undertaking.</p>

<p>Organized fraudsters have now embraced AI for communications on messaging platforms, employing text, voice, and even video calls, crafting illusions of celebrity interactions to deceive individuals.</p>

<p>Given AI’s capacity to simultaneously converse with thousands, the scale of deception and resulting harm is considerable.</p>

<p>The Ministry of Digital Affairs has adopted an “AI against AI” strategy, developing tools such as “Fraud Pattern Analysis” and “Anti-Fraud Radar”. These innovations daily identify thousands of dubious ads and e-commerce listings, facilitating their review and preemptive removal by major platforms.</p>

<p>Additionally, last year’s amendments to the Securities Investment Trust and Consulting Act introduced joint and several liabilities for platforms. Should victims attribute their deception to platform-hosted ads, which, despite reports, weren’t withdrawn within 24 hours, platforms must assume financial liability for the fraud.</p>

<p>In our continuous struggle against organized fraud, a balance of offense and defense is essential. As audio-visual synthesis technology becomes more sophisticated and misleading, we need more unfalsifiable measures to escalate the challenge of posting scam ads.</p>

<p>“Authenticity” stands as the paramount fraud deterrent. What better represents an individual’s identity than a hard-to-fake “digital signature”?</p>

<p>Although citizen digital certificates, corporate certificates, and organizational certificates have been utilized for years in Taiwan, prior amendments did not presume the same legal authority as signing on paper personally. The recent amendment to the Electronic Signature Act equates digital signatures with seal certificates, ensuring uniqueness and preventing forgery.</p>

<p>Looking ahead, investment ads on major platforms must authenticate personal involvement or genuine celebrity endorsement via digital signatures.</p>

<p>Should ads be flagged as suspicious and withdrawn, reposting under a new name won’t viable for fraudsters, as perpetual name changes at registration offices are impractical.</p>

<p>As we venture into the AI era, seeing can no longer be equated with believing. It’s imperative for defenders to proactively engage, leveraging AI against AI.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Hsin-Ting Fang</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Digital Industries" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital signatures, like seal certificates, ensure uniqueness and preventing forgery.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/key-hole-1262417_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/key-hole-1262417_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Summit for Democracy: Fostering right-respecting innovations</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%B0%91%E4%B8%BB%E5%B3%B0%E6%9C%83-%E4%BF%83%E9%80%B2%E5%B0%8A%E9%87%8D%E4%BA%BA%E6%AC%8A%E7%9A%84%E5%89%B5%E6%96%B0/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Summit for Democracy: Fostering right-respecting innovations" /><published>2024-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%B0%91%E4%B8%BB%E5%B3%B0%E6%9C%83-%E4%BF%83%E9%80%B2%E5%B0%8A%E9%87%8D%E4%BA%BA%E6%AC%8A%E7%9A%84%E5%89%B5%E6%96%B0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%B0%91%E4%B8%BB%E5%B3%B0%E6%9C%83-%E4%BF%83%E9%80%B2%E5%B0%8A%E9%87%8D%E4%BA%BA%E6%AC%8A%E7%9A%84%E5%89%B5%E6%96%B0/"><![CDATA[<p>Good local time. I am Audrey Tang, Taiwan’s digital minister.</p>

<p>It is a tremendous honor and privilege to once again fly the flag for Taiwan at the Summit for Democracy. The third edition of this global gathering of like-minded partners is of great importance given the challenges posed by AI and emerging technologies. The question we must all tackle is this: How best to foster right-respecting innovation in democratic societies?</p>

<p>In Taiwan, we believe the answer lies in our unshakeable belief in the power of co-creation to shape outcomes for the collective good. Case in point is our January elections — bad actors in the pay of authoritarians pulled out all stops, coming close to poisoning our information climate and interfering in the outcome.</p>

<p>But the government and people of all political persuasions stood as one in derailing insidious efforts to sow the seeds of division and discord. I am proud to say that in a year of balloting worldwide, we ably demonstrated what can be achieved by doubling down on democracy to free the future — together.</p>

<p>In the face of an alarming surge in cyberattacks, my Ministry of Digital Affairs, or the moda, unleashed a comprehensive defense. The stakes could not have been higher as Taiwan suffers a disproportionately high number of cyberattacks. These increased by more than six times year over year, and more than 33 times compared to the same quarter in 2022.</p>

<p>Our robust response ensured the stable operation of critical infrastructure and key websites through rigorous drills and tests. The 24/7 rapid response team and front-line monitoring proved effective, resulting in a 22 percent drop in DDoS incidents.</p>

<p>Another secret to our success was “pre-bunking” — a process in which poisons of the mind are treated before going viral. The point is to foster mutual trust instead of simply correcting facts. Research shows that a good prebunk explains tactics used to manipulate and has far-reaching benefits. By learning to recognize these tactics, the people are empowered to mount robust defenses.</p>

<p>Cofacts, a crowdsourced platform, also played a key role. Malicious and innocent reports alike were analyzed and assessed on the basis of accuracy and persuasiveness. With the assistance of real-time AI clarifications deployed by the g0v community, the people can make informed judgements on the veracity of content.</p>

<p>By supporting innovation in an open and transparent manner, with full respect to the Universal Declaration of Human Rights and its covenants, we are building bridges and finding solutions at home and abroad. After all, no democracy is an island — not even Taiwan.</p>

<p>With nearly 40 other countries holding elections this year, AI could amplify risks via deepfakes, echo chambers and micro-targeting. Extremism, polarization, and isolation, magnified by social media, are reshaping geopolitics.</p>

<p>As a responsible member of the international community, Taiwan is willing and able to work with all stakeholders in ensuring AI develops safely and sustainably. A democratic approach, not a technocratic one, is optimal for addressing this ethical, political and societal conundrum.</p>

<p>To this end, we are advancing Alignment Assemblies with The Collective Intelligence Project and world-class partners such as Anthropic, OpenAI, The GovLab and GETTING-Plurality research network. We have invited hundreds of thousands of everyday citizens to co-govern AI in the context of information integrity: Protecting users from harms; detecting and labeling AI content; requiring digital signatures for advertisers; making AI systems transparent; implementing citizen oversight of fact-checking and ongoing monitoring of AI incidents.</p>

<p>Deliberation strengthens societal resilience. In time, our AI norms will become part of the gold standard, further advancing Taiwan’s standing as a reliable and trusted partner. This is just one of the many ways Taiwan can help defend democracy by curing the ills of authoritarianism and building better tomorrows for all.</p>

<p>Blessings for your attention. Let’s cooperate closely in making 2024 a year of the democratic bounceback in which freedom, human rights and peace are advanced for all. Live long and … prosper!</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZIwebiobCD4" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Democracy Network" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[After all, no democracy is an island — not even Taiwan.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/h5hkoeil.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/h5hkoeil.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Should 窩心 be translated as nervous or heartwarming?</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E7%AA%A9%E5%BF%83-%E8%A9%B2%E7%BF%BB%E6%88%90%E7%84%A6%E6%85%AE%E9%82%84%E6%98%AF%E8%B2%BC%E5%BF%83/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Should 窩心 be translated as nervous or heartwarming?" /><published>2024-02-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E7%AA%A9%E5%BF%83-%E8%A9%B2%E7%BF%BB%E6%88%90%E7%84%A6%E6%85%AE%E9%82%84%E6%98%AF%E8%B2%BC%E5%BF%83</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E7%AA%A9%E5%BF%83-%E8%A9%B2%E7%BF%BB%E6%88%90%E7%84%A6%E6%85%AE%E9%82%84%E6%98%AF%E8%B2%BC%E5%BF%83/"><![CDATA[<p>How would you translate the sentence “他讓我很窩心”? Using Meta Llama 2’s language model to translate it, it will be translated as “He made me feel very nervous”.</p>

<p>“窩心” is used in Taiwan to make people feel warm and touching, while “nervous” has a completely opposite meaning in English.</p>

<p>But with Taiwan’s own TAIDE model, it will be accurately translated as “He made me feel very touched.</p>

<p>One of the ten topics in the AI Evaluation Center is “Accuracy”. If the AI model lacks accuracy, it may cause misunderstandings and even affect work and life.</p>

<p>For example, in the medical field, inaccurate translation may lead to misdiagnosis or delayed treatment; in the financial field, it may lead to transaction losses; in the legal field, it may lead to litigation.</p>

<p>Second, if we do not have a language model that fits the cultural environment, or if a foreign language model does not have accurate evaluation capabilities when it enters our market, it is possible that other countries’ language models will use the most accurate evaluation capabilities. Cheap methods will be casually used to deal with the past, enter the market and be used by the public, causing adverse effects.</p>

<p>Finally, who should be the standard for “accuracy”? This is another question that many people ask. The AI Evaluation Center does not make up standard answers, but relies on normative sources, such as authoritative educational institutions like the National Institute of Education, as the basis for accuracy.</p>

<p>Going back to the example at the beginning, in the initial training data of Llama 2, it is obvious that there is a lot of original data that “warmth” means discomfort, which is why it chose to translate it that way. Are you saying that this is wrong? It cannot be said that it is wrong, but it does not meet Taiwan’s requirements for accuracy.</p>

<p>That is why it is very important to choose the unit to measure the accuracy against. If we expand it further, the accuracy must also take into account the needs of different businesses. When language models are used in a business environment, further fine-tuning and customization is often required according to communication standards.</p>

<p>For example, many fields have what we commonly call “jargon” — a customized vocabulary. People in the same business can understand these words at a glance, but people outside the field may not necessarily know them. Another reason is that the same words can have completely different meanings in different industries.</p>

<p>For example, official documents written by law firms and government agencies have very clear jargon, and outsiders may not necessarily understand this specialized vocabulary. At this point, we need to build a dataset within an organization to fine-tune and further adapt the previously trained AI model.</p>

<p>When all areas of life can freely fine-tune translation models, text translators will be relegated to the task of final proofreading and model tuning — this could happen within the next two to three years.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Michelle Chen</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Digital Industries" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[When language models are used in a business environment, further fine-tuning and customization is often required according to communication standards.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/sew-517026_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/sew-517026_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">AI adaptation</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/AI-%E8%AA%BF%E9%81%A9/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AI adaptation" /><published>2024-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/AI-%E8%AA%BF%E9%81%A9</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/AI-%E8%AA%BF%E9%81%A9/"><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to AI governance, in addition to relevant legislation, what I want to emphasize is the “forward-looking” AI adaptation mechanism.</p>

<p>Why forward-looking?</p>

<p>For example, a few years ago, the Office of Science and Technology Newspaper and I made a video to show the public how easy it is to use cheap cell phones and laptops to deepfake my own image.</p>

<p>In this way, before large-scale damage occurs, we can take a step forward to prevent harm, and at the same time, let the public understand how to mitigate the risks in advance.</p>

<p>The so-called AI adaptation mechanism has two forward-looking directions: one is to quickly discover new harms through the participation of all people; the other is how to quickly inform practitioners after discovery, and to set a boundary in front of harms to guide practitioners to develop in a safe direction.</p>

<p>Because AI is a general-purpose technology, it is difficult to assess all possible harms in the laboratory R&amp;D stage, so there should be a systematic way to understand the impact on society when it is actually deployed through at least biannual scrutiny.</p>

<p>But does this mean that the standards and definitions for assessing harms are tied to a small group of people?</p>

<p>Not exactly. We can adopt two approaches. First, we can adopt “voluntary notification”, which means that anyone who discovers potential hazards will have a place to raise their hands and discuss with others in a similar situation. Secondly, we can adopt a “random sampling” approach, whereby stratified sampling telephone interviews are conducted after determining the proportion of the population. However, this traditional method of conducting public opinion surveys has its drawbacks. Usually, only multiple-choice questions can be asked, and open-ended questions cannot be asked further.</p>

<p>To tackle this challenge, we can utilize the “deliberative polling” method, combining deliberative discussions and random sampling, by inviting several hundred or even thousands of statistically representative people across the country to join the video conference in groups, and brainstorm with each other. This will allow for in-depth discussions and allow more people to participate.</p>

<p>I hope that people who are not yet using AI, or who have just been affected by it, will have a chance to understand it through the deliberation process, and put it into their own life contexts: if their friends, family, and even their companies start to utilize advanced generative AI, how are they going to adapt? In this way, we will be able to plan ahead and respond to the needs of society immediately.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Vanessa Chiang</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Democracy Network" /><category term="Digital Industries" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Are the standards and definitions for assessing harms are tied to a small group of people?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/boat-1834397_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/boat-1834397_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Can Superalignment help AI safety?</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E8%B6%85%E6%99%BA%E6%85%A7%E5%B0%8D%E9%BD%8A-%E8%83%BD%E6%89%93%E9%80%A0%E6%9B%B4%E5%AE%89%E5%85%A8-AI/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Can Superalignment help AI safety?" /><published>2023-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E3%80%8C%E8%B6%85%E6%99%BA%E6%85%A7%E5%B0%8D%E9%BD%8A%E3%80%8D%E8%83%BD%E6%89%93%E9%80%A0%E6%9B%B4%E5%AE%89%E5%85%A8-AI%EF%BC%9F</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E8%B6%85%E6%99%BA%E6%85%A7%E5%B0%8D%E9%BD%8A-%E8%83%BD%E6%89%93%E9%80%A0%E6%9B%B4%E5%AE%89%E5%85%A8-AI/"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, Jensen Huang — co-founder, president and CEO of U.S. multinational tech giant Nvidia Corp. — said AI will surpass human beings in the next five years. In keeping with this seeming fait accompli, Sam Altman – CEO of OpenAI – said AI development cannot be stopped.</p>

<p>These fears are shared by Ilya Sutskever — co-founder and chief scientist at OpenAI. But his farsighted <a href="https://openai.com/blog/introducing-superalignment">superalignment project</a> may offer a viable way of avoiding what can only be seen as a major societal-scale risk.</p>

<p>For me, superalignment means automated alignment — ensuring AI continues to fit human expectations. But we need to first understand the formulation of AI as a two-step process, namely pre-training and fine-tuning, before going deeper.</p>

<p>Pre-training is akin to taking a mass of data and compressing it into a model, which can then produce answers according to the commonality of the obtained data. For example, the model may recognize the commonality of faces, such as outlines and colors. After receiving instructions, it can draw a new face. However, when training data is insufficient for the task at hand, the results may appear plausible, but are actually wrong. This is more commonly known as an AI “hallucination.”</p>

<p>Fine-tuning helps to teach the model to output answers acceptable to humans through rewarding good ones and dissuading bad ones. Confabulated and harmful responses are counterproductive, and transparency associated with confidence levels are important. If the answers are not based on the training materials, the model must say so.</p>

<p>Superalignment is essentially about leveraging existing AI systems in assisting humans to do most of the fine-tuning work.</p>

<p>For example, a judge can hear a complex patent infringement case without being an expert in the field. As long as the proceedings involve lawyers specialized in the particular area, the judge needs only determine whether the issues are in accordance with the law. Similarly, superalignment puts humans in the judge’s place.</p>

<p>Going forward, people can co-create a Constitutional AI document, and  AI models can be aligned to the prescribed norms as The Collective Intelligence Project and Anthropic have ably <a href="https://www.anthropic.com/index/collective-constitutional-ai-aligning-a-language-model-with-public-input">demonstrated</a>. Case in point, a small AI, trained in the United Nations’ Universal Declaration of Human Rights, can then calibrate a larger AI model’s alignment.</p>

<p>As policymakers, our job is to send clear signals to the market through tailored initiatives and state investment. The recently opened AI Evaluation Center is playing its part by issuing a 10-point plan governing AI models. This comprises safety, resilience, accuracy, accountability, privacy, explainability, fairness, transparency, reliability and security. If a model proves problematic, it will not be banned immediately, but the government cannot encourage its deployment.</p>

<p>When I assisted Apple Inc.’s Siri team from 2010 to 2016, the most important thing at that time was accuracy and harmlessness. As alignment techniques mature, I believe AI systems with frequent hallucinations will come to be avoided by investors.</p>

<p>This is like the revelation that some gasses used in refrigerators can destroy the ozone layer; signatories to the Montreal Protocol agreed they should be banned. It was a clear signal to the manufacturers that such processes must be adjusted quickly or the product will cease to exist. Conversely, when more stable and safe AI systems emerge in the market, subsequent consumer response and investment will ensure the industry does not go astray.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Vanessa Chiang</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Digital Industries" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[AI systems with frequent hallucinations will come to be avoided by investors.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/steampunk-3169877.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/steampunk-3169877.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Echoes of the Past, Voices of the Future</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%98%94%E6%97%A5%E5%9B%9E%E9%9F%BF-%E6%9C%AA%E4%BE%86%E4%B9%8B%E8%81%B2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Echoes of the Past, Voices of the Future" /><published>2023-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%98%94%E6%97%A5%E5%9B%9E%E9%9F%BF-%E6%9C%AA%E4%BE%86%E4%B9%8B%E8%81%B2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%98%94%E6%97%A5%E5%9B%9E%E9%9F%BF-%E6%9C%AA%E4%BE%86%E4%B9%8B%E8%81%B2/"><![CDATA[<p>Have you heard The Beatles’ new song “Now and Then?” Recently, the legendary band, now down to Paul McCartney and Ringo Starr, released its “latest single.” The widely acclaimed offering is a prime example of AI for the collective good.</p>

<p>The song was recorded by John Lennon at home, singing and playing the piano into a tape recorder. For years after his untimely death, band members tried to reproduce the song, but the task was shelved due to the overly muddled quality of the recording. It was not until the recent maturation of AI-based technology, which can differentiate between singing and piano sounds, that a poignant and poetic finale was provided for The Beatles.</p>

<p>Listening to Lennon’s voice, I am reminded of the similarly prematurely lost cybersecurity luminary and founder of Let’s Encrypt, Peter Eckersley. In recent years, Eckersley observed that while AI was evolving rapidly, it also began to pose risks to human society. Last year he founded The AI Objectives Institute (AOI) , with the hope that AI could “help humanity become better.”</p>

<p>But in the midst of fervent preparations, Eckersley was lost to cancer. Fortunately, with widespread support, AOI continues to drive numerous experiments and studies to this day. One pilot project is Talk to the City.</p>

<p>The AI tool categorizes online comments, videos or statements into themes representing various opinions. Beyond creating visual graphs to fully present everyone’s statements, its conversational language models also reflect data-informed thinking patterns. This affords more people the chance to understand different viewpoints.</p>

<p>Previously, the Ministry of Digital Affairs utilized this mechanism during the Ideathon, organizing participants’ thoughts on topics such as AI ethics and government use of data and AI. Those who did not participate in the workshop could understand participants’ views, as well as engage in “dialogues” with AI to discover intersections of differing opinions, making decisions that stand on common ground without harming anyone.</p>

<p>The experiences of “Now And Then” and Talk to the City show the world how AI transcends time and tide, turning the impossible into possible: a beloved music group disbanded for over 50 years can release a new song, and important discussions can continue developing after conclusion. It is evident that if AI is properly integrated into public infrastructures, it has the potential to help humanity become better.</p>

<p>A good place to start is with the Government Data Open Platform. This integrates AI public code, making it easier for users to find the open data they need and give feedback for corrections. In addition, we will prioritize the municipal services number “1999” of local governments in the next four years,  in order to alleviate the administrative burden on civil servants, as well as enhance access to public services.</p>

<p>Going forward, AI won’t be merely a digital tool for occasional use every now and then. Through open-source collaboration and societal evaluation, we are shaping up a foundation where responsible AI enables us to free the future — together.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sheau-Tyng Peng</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Democracy Network" /><category term="Plural Innovation" /><category term="Digital Strategy" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If AI is properly integrated into public infrastructures, it has the potential to help humanity become better.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/beatles-5364078_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/beatles-5364078_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Information Integrity Ensures Online Freedom</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%AE%88%E8%AD%B7%E8%B3%87%E8%A8%8A%E5%AE%8C%E6%95%B4-%E7%B6%B2%E8%B7%AF%E6%89%8D%E6%9C%89%E8%87%AA%E7%94%B1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Information Integrity Ensures Online Freedom" /><published>2023-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%AE%88%E8%AD%B7%E8%B3%87%E8%A8%8A%E5%AE%8C%E6%95%B4-%E7%B6%B2%E8%B7%AF%E6%89%8D%E6%9C%89%E8%87%AA%E7%94%B1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%AE%88%E8%AD%B7%E8%B3%87%E8%A8%8A%E5%AE%8C%E6%95%B4-%E7%B6%B2%E8%B7%AF%E6%89%8D%E6%9C%89%E8%87%AA%E7%94%B1/"><![CDATA[<p>During the National Day holiday, I took a personal trip to Kyoto, Japan, for the United Nations Internet Governance Forum. Established in 2006, the IGF has been the U.N.’s primary conference on digital policy. This year, it attracted over 6,000 attendees from 178 countries.</p>

<p>The first session I joined was “DFI: Principles to Action.” Representing Taiwan in April 2022, during my tenure as minister without portfolio, I signed the DFI alongside representatives from more than 60 countries. Together, we pledged to shape the internet as a resilient platform that upholds freedom, human rights and mutual trust.</p>

<p>During group discussions, my colleagues from the National Institute of Cyber Security and I, both virtually and in person, joined the government subgroup. We shared strategies to prevent the internet from falling prey to authoritarian regimes. Among attendees, concerns about the risks posed by AI were paramount.</p>

<p>Recently, U.S. think tank Freedom House published its annual “Freedom on the Net” report, showing that while AI brings rapid development and convenience, it also unlocks the potential for totalitarian surveillance and misinformation. This finding dovetails with the decline of global internet freedom for 13 consecutive years.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Yoshihide Kishida of Japan mentioned in his speech that, based on the consensus from the G7 Hiroshima Summit in May, Japan will lead discussions on the “Hiroshima AI Process.” This initiative invites stakeholders from industry, government, academia and society worldwide to ensure trustworthy AI.</p>

<p>Building digital trust is an urgent task for governments and vital for the survival of the digital industry. During my stay in Kyoto, I met with Nick Clegg, president of Meta’s Global Affairs, to discuss the rampant growth of AI-enhanced foreign information manipulation. He expressed candid concerns that if the scale becomes too much for even Facebook’s current third-party fact-checking program, it will pose a significant threat to the integrity of online information.</p>

<p>Clegg’s concerns are valid. In a world where face-to-face interaction is often not possible, mutual trust becomes the bedrock of digital interaction. This is essential for community collaboration and transactions.</p>

<p>I am proud to say Taiwan ranked first in the Asia-Pacific region in the latest “Freedom on the Net” report. In my view, this achievement reflects our prioritization of digital trust as a foundational pillar.</p>

<p>“Information Integrity” is the cornerstone of trust, whether it’s identifying an individual, an organization, or a document. Ensuring clear identification of entities in the digital realm is the first step towards building mutual trust.</p>

<p>From the “Government URL Shortener” service to the establishment of the “AI Product and System Testing and Certification Center” and amendments to the “Cyber Security Management Act” and “Electronic Signature Act,” we have consistently enhanced our digital trust infrastructure over the past year. We are now collaborating with telecom providers to create the “111” government-exclusive SMS platform. This ensures that government agency messages cannot be spoofed, offering stronger protection for information integrity.</p>

<p>While in Kyoto, many new friends approached me, expressing high regard for Taiwan’s digital democracy. This reinforced my belief that in the online world, there are no geographical distances, only proximity of values. We will continue to harness trust technologies, joining with democratic partners in the digital realm.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sheau-Tyng Peng</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Democracy Network" /><category term="Digital Service" /><category term="Digital Industries" /><category term="Cyber Security" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA["Information Integrity" is the cornerstone of trust, whether it's identifying an individual, an organization, or a document.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/F8UiIPuaIAAcmr5.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/F8UiIPuaIAAcmr5.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Per aspera ad astra</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E7%A9%BF%E8%B6%8A%E6%8C%91%E6%88%B0-%E4%BB%A5%E9%81%94%E6%98%9F%E8%BE%B0/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Per aspera ad astra" /><published>2023-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E7%A9%BF%E8%B6%8A%E6%8C%91%E6%88%B0%EF%BC%8C%E4%BB%A5%E9%81%94%E6%98%9F%E8%BE%B0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E7%A9%BF%E8%B6%8A%E6%8C%91%E6%88%B0-%E4%BB%A5%E9%81%94%E6%98%9F%E8%BE%B0/"><![CDATA[<p>A few days ago, I had a video conversation with Meredith Whittaker, President of Signal Foundation, on Taiwan Plus, the Ministry of Culture’s English audio-visual platform, an experience I found deeply insightful.</p>

<p>Signal is an open source communication software that uses end-to-end encryption technology. Whittaker specifically pointed out that not only is the app safeguarded against eavesdropping, the encryption extends to “metadata”, which is content that can indirectly identify personal information. In other words, the Signal Foundation cannot obtain any personal information. If anyone has concerns, they can verify and fix the source code together.</p>

<p>As one of Time Magazine’s top 100 most influential people in AI, Whittaker has unique insights into the internet industry. She believes that a small number of cross-border platforms have formed a monopolistic cycle. They first establish a huge infrastructure, with significant investment to train AI for precise delivery, and then collect massive amounts of personal data through advertising technology. After making profits, they continue to adjust the AI model, so as to continuously use personal data to make profits.</p>

<p>Therefore, as a non-profit organization, Signal adheres to its core philosophy to “ensure meaningful communication privacy always exists” and hopes to break this monopolistic cycle.</p>

<p>“We navigate what we navigate with that North Star in mind.” Regarding the development prospects, Whittaker gave a poetic comment, which also highlighted that the journey ahead is extensive. The monopoly cycle not only affects personal privacy security, but also hinders industrial innovation.</p>

<p>According to statistics from European telecom operators, a handful of cross-border platforms account for 55% of internet traffic. As a result, the telecom industry must continue to expand additional resources and infrastructure in order to maintain normal operations. In the long run, the autonomy of individuals and small and medium-sized enterprises on the net will inevitably be reduced.</p>

<p>Talent and creativity are Taiwan’s most important advantages in the critical decade ahead. To prevent a few operators from monopolizing resources, network bandwidth is the core of “digital public infrastructure”, facilitating a conducive environment for talents to effectively display their creativity with new business models. Therefore, in September this year, the national 5G dedicated frequency private network promoted by the Administration for Digital Industries (ADI) officially began.</p>

<p>Most prominently, the “5G Vertical Industry Application Promotion Group”, which was established by 13 industry association partners together with the ADI, selected 33 practical application cases through public selection, including TV stations using XR (covering three types of extended reality: virtual, augmented, and mixed), real-time remote virtual and real visits, Kaohsiung Exhibition Hall’s 5G exhibition private network system, etc., have been chosen as partners for the next fifteen months, in order to accelerate digital upgrades in various industries.</p>

<p>“Per aspera ad astra” is a Latin proverb that means “crossing challenges to reach the stars.” This notion came to my mind following the conversation with Whittaker. It is also what I think is the best way to describe the digital transformation across industries. Starting from the construction of 5G, we will continue to open up channels so that the North Star in everyone’s heart can become the most dazzling star.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sheau-Tyng Peng</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Digital Industries" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The monopolistic cycle not only jeopardizes individual privacy but also stifles innovation across industries.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/north-star-2869817_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/north-star-2869817_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>