<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-10-15T01:28:52+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/feed.xml</id><author><name>PDIS</name></author><entry><title type="html">Per aspera ad astra</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E7%A9%BF%E8%B6%8A%E6%8C%91%E6%88%B0-%E4%BB%A5%E9%81%94%E6%98%9F%E8%BE%B0/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Per aspera ad astra" /><published>2023-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E7%A9%BF%E8%B6%8A%E6%8C%91%E6%88%B0%EF%BC%8C%E4%BB%A5%E9%81%94%E6%98%9F%E8%BE%B0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E7%A9%BF%E8%B6%8A%E6%8C%91%E6%88%B0-%E4%BB%A5%E9%81%94%E6%98%9F%E8%BE%B0/"><![CDATA[<p>A few days ago, I had a video conversation with Meredith Whittaker, President of Signal Foundation, on Taiwan Plus, the Ministry of Culture’s English audio-visual platform, an experience I found deeply insightful.</p>

<p>Signal is an open source communication software that uses end-to-end encryption technology. Whittaker specifically pointed out that not only is the app safeguarded against eavesdropping, the encryption extends to “metadata”, which is content that can indirectly identify personal information. In other words, the Signal Foundation cannot obtain any personal information. If anyone has concerns, they can verify and fix the source code together.</p>

<p>As one of Time Magazine’s top 100 most influential people in AI, Whittaker has unique insights into the internet industry. She believes that a small number of cross-border platforms have formed a monopolistic cycle. They first establish a huge infrastructure, with significant investment to train AI for precise delivery, and then collect massive amounts of personal data through advertising technology. After making profits, they continue to adjust the AI model, so as to continuously use personal data to make profits.</p>

<p>Therefore, as a non-profit organization, Signal adheres to its core philosophy to “ensure meaningful communication privacy always exists” and hopes to break this monopolistic cycle.</p>

<p>“We navigate what we navigate with that North Star in mind.” Regarding the development prospects, Whittaker gave a poetic comment, which also highlighted that the journey ahead is extensive. The monopoly cycle not only affects personal privacy security, but also hinders industrial innovation.</p>

<p>According to statistics from European telecom operators, a handful of cross-border platforms account for 55% of internet traffic. As a result, the telecom industry must continue to expand additional resources and infrastructure in order to maintain normal operations. In the long run, the autonomy of individuals and small and medium-sized enterprises on the net will inevitably be reduced.</p>

<p>Talent and creativity are Taiwan’s most important advantages in the critical decade ahead. To prevent a few operators from monopolizing resources, network bandwidth is the core of “digital public infrastructure”, facilitating a conducive environment for talents to effectively display their creativity with new business models. Therefore, in September this year, the national 5G dedicated frequency private network promoted by the Administration for Digital Industries (ADI) officially began.</p>

<p>Most prominently, the “5G Vertical Industry Application Promotion Group”, which was established by 13 industry association partners together with the ADI, selected 33 practical application cases through public selection, including TV stations using XR (covering three types of extended reality: virtual, augmented, and mixed), real-time remote virtual and real visits, Kaohsiung Exhibition Hall’s 5G exhibition private network system, etc., have been chosen as partners for the next fifteen months, in order to accelerate digital upgrades in various industries.</p>

<p>“Per aspera ad astra” is a Latin proverb that means “crossing challenges to reach the stars.” This notion came to my mind following the conversation with Whittaker. It is also what I think is the best way to describe the digital transformation across industries. Starting from the construction of 5G, we will continue to open up channels so that the North Star in everyone’s heart can become the most dazzling star.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sheau-Tyng Peng</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Digital Industries" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The monopolistic cycle not only jeopardizes individual privacy but also stifles innovation across industries.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/north-star-2869817_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/north-star-2869817_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Digital Democracy in the Age of AI</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%95%B8%E4%BD%8D%E6%B0%91%E4%B8%BB-AI-%E6%99%82%E4%BB%A3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Digital Democracy in the Age of AI" /><published>2023-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%95%B8%E4%BD%8D%E6%B0%91%E4%B8%BB-AI-%E6%99%82%E4%BB%A3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%95%B8%E4%BD%8D%E6%B0%91%E4%B8%BB-AI-%E6%99%82%E4%BB%A3/"><![CDATA[<p>Good local time everyone, my name is Audrey Tang and I am Taiwan’s digital minister and chair of the National Institute of Cyber Security.</p>

<p>It is a tremendous honor and a privilege to deliver the keynote at SITRA’s online event exploring ways of shaping technology to support, not hollow out, democracy. This gathering of the enlightened takes on great significance given its staging in conjunction with International Day of Democracy — an opportunity to double down on delivering compassionate, effective and responsive governance tailored to the needs of the people.</p>

<p>There is no question that democracy is facing unprecedented challenges at every turn from authoritarians seeking to harness the power of AI to destabilize and undermine our free and open societies. These efforts come in all shapes and sizes, but the most insidious ones target our fabric of trust, polluting social media platforms founded on Article 19 of the United Nations Universal Declaration of Human Rights — the right to freedom of opinion and expression.</p>

<p>In 2016, we witnessed a bellwether of sorts in public communication. The venerable Associated Press Style Guide declared the word “Internet” would no longer be capitalized, signifying its pervasive use. Unfortunately, this ubiquity also cleared a path for persuasion industries to engage in large-scale personal data collection and overturn privacy norms, marooning many on desert islands of polarization. Deepfakes — going fully interactive this year — have sullied online interactions, opening the door wider for fraud and manipulation at an unprecedented scale.</p>

<p>Consequently, democracy finds itself at a low ebb. Autocracy is on the rise, utilizing crafted censorship and electronic surveillance systems. The truth of the matter is global internet freedom has declined for the 12th consecutive year. Today, only a billion people live under the umbrella of democratic systems, while more than double toil under authoritarian rule.</p>

<p>It is said that there are two sides to every coin. While certain emerging technologies bolster authoritarians, some may yet be employed to revitalize democracy. How best to combat the pervasiveness of online harms? The solution lies in plurality, or technologies for collaborative diversity, to increase the bandwidth of democracy. Polis is a prime example of this ethos.</p>

<p>Taiwan started its journey with Polis in 2015 when Uber and sharing economy startups took the world by storm. The relentless march of innovation and profit clashed with the livelihood of taxi drivers, triggering legal action and protests. This conflict also raged in Taiwan, and we were fortunate to have Polis to track its route and derive shared wisdom from flame wars.</p>

<p>The beauty of Polis is that participants and opinions are visualized on the same page, as well as how divided the groups are. Despite initially polarized opinions, Polis consistently promotes common points of view to bridge divides. Polis does not just provide a visual mapping of democratic input, it also produces an interactive report, updated in real time.</p>

<p>This has applications for all issues of international import. Twice Taiwan has worked with fellow democracies like Finland through Polis. The first in 2019 amid escalating trade tensions, when some feared Taiwan would be caught in the middle of an epic struggle and sidelined from economic integration. Through the AIT@40 Digital Dialogues, ideas were canvassed across the Indo-Pacific on how to increase defense, economic and people-to-people exchanges between Taiwan and the U.S. These were then swiftly implemented by both sides.</p>

<p>In 2020, Taiwan explored privacy-preserving contact tracing and various pandemic countermeasures, again with avid global participation. It is notable that this was not limited to Polis opinion surveys — solutions were co-created. In recognizing which were aligned with societal values, civic hackers across the world proceeded to animate the ideas via hackathons.</p>

<p>This year, Taiwan is taking Polis to a whole new level. In response to the rapid popularization of AI, the Ministry of Digital Affairs has joined the Collective Intelligence Project to launch <a href="https://cip.org/alignmentassemblies">Alignment Assemblies</a>. Other partners include OpenAI, Anthropic, the GovLab and GETTING-Plurality research network. The goal is to give the people a chance to contribute to the safe and sustainable development of AI, as well as identify and mitigate risks caused by this emerging technology.</p>

<p>Throughout July, we co-created with the people through Polis, exploring topics on democratizing AI futures and setting the agenda for face-to-face deliberative workshops in August and September. The records will soon be published as open data, facilitating the training of AI language models aligned with Taiwan’s distinct experiences.</p>

<p>To ensure authentic voices are heard in Alignment Assemblies, two features were introduced by polis.tw, which is maintained by the PDIS team at the National Institute of Cyber Security. First, we extended Polis to integrate with trusted external sign-on systems, ensuring the authenticity of participants.</p>

<p>Furthermore, with the help of AI Objectives Institute, the <a href="https://www.talktothe.city/">Talk to the City</a> site shown here provides real-time AI-assisted summarization, translation and interaction. This chatroom empowers individuals to engage in nuanced dialogue with diverse opinion clusters, deepening cross-cultural understanding and empathy.</p>

<p>Now, take a look at <a href="https://talk.polis.tw/">this picture</a> — every dot represents an opinion and sparkles like a star in the darkness of the background. The holistic reflections form constellations, providing us directions on alignment. For many participants, this is the first time they interacted with AI in the context of deliberation. This occurred not as a solo conversation, but as an evolving group discussion for the collective good.</p>

<p>In terms of AI governance, we believe that a democratic approach — not a technocratic one — is the optimal answer to what is an ethical and political conundrum of global proportions. The bottom line is experts simply cannot catch all use cases nor effects. Just as with climate change, comprehensive statistics are needed on potential harms, including over-reliance, emotional effects and information manipulation.</p>

<p>Unlike climate change, interactions with AI are deeply personal. All indicators must be shared in a thoroughly privacy-preserving manner. It is felt the safest way to operate is to form coalitions of data holders and researchers, mediated through trusted data altruism organizations, to safeguard processing and aggregation of non-personal data on harms and preferences.</p>

<p>Thanks to zero-knowledge proofs, privacy-enhancing technologies and a GDPR-compliant version of Polis pioneered by SITRA, worldwide Alignment Assemblies are well within reach. Step by step, let us build consensus on the boundaries of AI and shepherd its ongoing development, with interconnected local assemblies delivering specific directions for particular political and regulatory contexts.</p>

<p>In closing, I invite all and sundry to participate in Polis conversations of scale, and employ pioneering initiatives in the realms of collective intelligence to rein in societal risks while safeguarding human rights and democracy for generations to come. By drawing on the collaboration, curiosity, courage and vision of the people, we can chart a deliberative and sustainable course for global governance and free the future — together.</p>

<p>Blessings for your attention and time, and congratulations to SITRA for this exciting event. Live long and … prosper!</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Z6wLJ_lDsks" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Rosalind Liu, Wendy Hsueh</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Democracy Network" /><category term="Digital Strategy" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[For many participants, this was their first interaction with AI in a deliberative context.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/2023-09-11.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/2023-09-11.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Trust is the key</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E9%97%9C%E9%8D%B5%E5%9C%A8%E6%96%BC%E4%BF%A1%E4%BB%BB/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trust is the key" /><published>2023-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E9%97%9C%E9%8D%B5%E5%9C%A8%E6%96%BC%E4%BF%A1%E4%BB%BB</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E9%97%9C%E9%8D%B5%E5%9C%A8%E6%96%BC%E4%BF%A1%E4%BB%BB/"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, Vitalik Buterin, co-founder of the renowned open-source project Ethereum, came to Taiwan to receive a Gold Card, granting him residency in our country. During our conversation at the “Plurality Taipei” event, participants raised a philosophical question: Who is qualified to “prove” everyone’s identity in a decentralized cross-border community that cannot rely on the government?</p>

<p>Buterin believes that verification through interpersonal “social graphs” is more aligned to the spirit of Plurality. For example, being introduced into a community by friends you know is a kind of social graph.</p>

<p>Another method is “biometrics”: Verifying identity through fingerprints and iris recognition is also a widely used approach today.  Co-initiated by OpenAI founder Sam Altman and officially launched at the end of July, the cryptocurrency “Worldcoin” is a recent bold attempt to apply biometrics.</p>

<p>To obtain Worldcoin, you first must undergo authentication by scanning your iris with a sphere called “the Orb.” The initial intent behind this mechanism is to prevent generative AI from impersonating humans. However, balancing the offline storage of sensitive data while achieving decentralized verification remains a significant challenge for Worldcoin.</p>

<p>Buterin posits that, for Worldcoin’s use of biometrics, even if they attempt to mitigate privacy risks through encryption, there still exists the risk of data breaches and malicious use.</p>

<p>Another way to identify a social graph is to verify a person’s identity with a social circle, which requires the individual’s consent. Buterin’s reminder brings to mind the report “Data Coalitions and Escrow Agents” published by RadicalxChange Foundation in June.</p>

<p>The core concept of this report revolves around the “contextual boundaries” of personal data, meaning that the significance generated within a social graph often implicates many individuals’ privacy. Thus, personal data should not be used outside its original purpose unless explicitly approved by the parties involved. Only by transforming it into non-personal data, with full protection of contextual boundary, can it circulate freely and be used safely.</p>

<p>The report pointed out that the social value of data is far greater than the price of personal information as a commodity. Therefore, the most assuring mode of operation is a coalition formed by data holders and data users, employing trusted third parties to ensure fairness and trustworthiness during data transformation. At this juncture, “privacy-enhancing technologies” serve as the crucial line of defense.</p>

<p>Building on the foundational demonstration of this year’s “<a href="https://www.data-sports.tw/">Sports Data Altruism Service</a>”, the Ministry of Digital Affairs will subsequently release “<a href="https://join.gov.tw/policies/detail/ada473f2-7a4b-42ca-984b-740da54e6915">Guidelines for Data Altruism Operations</a>” and “<a href="https://hackmd.io/@petworks/rJ-UOh9Rn">Guidelines for Applications of Privacy-Enhancing Technologies</a>,” providing technical details and methods of application. In my opinion, this not only has the opportunity to become a new cross-border digital authentication method, but also will open up an public good ecosystem of non-personal data.</p>

<p>After all, whether it’s identity verification or data utilization, the key ultimately lies in “trust.” It’s only with mutual trust between individuals that cross-border identities become meaningful, and non-personal data can fully realize its value.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sheau-Tyng Peng</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Plural Innovation" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The most assuring mode of operation is a coalition formed by data holders and data users.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/key-2471007_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/key-2471007_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Case for Democratizing AI</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E7%84%A1%E6%B3%95%E5%A3%93%E7%B8%AE%E7%9A%84%E6%BC%94%E7%AE%97%E6%B3%95/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Case for Democratizing AI" /><published>2023-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E7%84%A1%E6%B3%95%E5%A3%93%E7%B8%AE%E7%9A%84%E6%BC%94%E7%AE%97%E6%B3%95</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E7%84%A1%E6%B3%95%E5%A3%93%E7%B8%AE%E7%9A%84%E6%BC%94%E7%AE%97%E6%B3%95/"><![CDATA[<p>A few months ago, “Clarkesworld,” the esteemed sci-fi magazine, temporarily halted submissions. The reason? A dramatic increase in machine-generated entries as a byproduct of the popularization of generative AI. The irony of AI-generated sci-fi and an overwhelmed editorial staff is no laughing matter — it reveals deep-seated concerns held by many.</p>

<p>The multifaceted capabilities of AI services extend to translation, art, coding and even inspiration, making them indispensable in numerous sectors. Yet, the “Clarkesworld” response is a mere symptom of the societal impact of AI. Even more concerning is the ability of AI to replicate faces and voices, leading to sophisticated fraud and eroding the bedrock of interpersonal trust. When weaponized by totalitarian regimes and cybercriminals, this poses a severe threat to democratic systems.</p>

<p>On top of these concerns, the most sophisticated generative AIs are each trained by a single organization. This leads to a one-size-fits-all model unintentionally echoing the biases of its creators. As a result, the diverse cultural nuances of a global audience are frequently neglected or mishandled.</p>

<p>At London Tech Week, which I attended at the invitation of the organizers in June, a cross-sector consensus emerged from intense discussions on such issues: The future of AI must avoid centralization and instead adopt a diverse democratic model. To maintain a delicate balance between the advancement of AI and safety, we need to move away from placing unwavering trust in a handful of developers. Instead, we must provide channels for <a href="https://fortune.com/2023/06/20/why-picking-citizens-at-random-best-way-to-govern-ai-revolution-tech-politics/">citizens across the world</a> to participate and collaboratively build a globally trusted AI assurance framework, hallmarked by shared ethical standards and usage principles.</p>

<p>During these dialogues, I reflected on one of my favorite sci-fi novellas, “The Lifecycle of Software Objects” by the tremendous Ted Chiang. The narrative features a future tech firm merging AI and VR to create virtual life forms. Two of the protagonists come to understand that AI, like a living organism, requires continual nurturing and education to evolve.</p>

<p>“Experience is algorithmically incompressible,” Chiang writes, reflecting on the process of raising virtual life. “If you want to create the common sense that comes from twenty years of being in the world, you need to devote twenty years to the task.”</p>

<p>This simple but profound insight provides a roadmap for AI democratization: Sustainable consensus can only be achieved through public participation. This is why I joined the Collective Intelligence Project (CIP), alongside industry partners such as OpenAI and Anthropic, in launching Alignment Assemblies. Taiwan is setting a global precedent in <a href="https://talk.polis.tw/">aligning AI values</a> through civic deliberation, in what we term an “<a href="https://ideathon.tw/polis">ideathon</a>.”</p>

<p>“The Lifecycle of Software Objects” ends with the AI entities exhibiting independent thought, emotional intelligence and deep social connections due to the protagonists’ steadfast patience. I envision the future of AI, starting with pioneering Alignment Assemblies, to mirror this evolution. Let’s draw upon the rich tapestry of diverse experiences and the “<a href="https://cip.org/research/democratizing-ai">wisdom of crowds</a>” accumulated over thousands of years, and shape AI into trusted and wise partners dedicated to societal well-being.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sheau-Tyng Peng, Gisele Chou, Mashbean Huang</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Digital Strategy" /><category term="Democracy Network" /><category term="Cyber Security" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you want to create the common sense that comes from twenty years of being in the world, you need to devote twenty years to the task.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/20230803.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/20230803.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Public-Private Collaboration for Precise Fraud Prevention</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%85%AC%E7%A7%81%E8%81%AF%E9%98%B2-%E7%B2%BE%E6%BA%96%E6%89%93%E8%A9%90/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Public-Private Collaboration for Precise Fraud Prevention" /><published>2023-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%85%AC%E7%A7%81%E8%81%AF%E9%98%B2-%E7%B2%BE%E6%BA%96%E6%89%93%E8%A9%90</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%85%AC%E7%A7%81%E8%81%AF%E9%98%B2-%E7%B2%BE%E6%BA%96%E6%89%93%E8%A9%90/"><![CDATA[<p>Some time ago, the Executive Yuan ratified the “Fraud Action Program 1.5” and established the “Fraud Prevention Office”. Concurrently, I received requests from my column readers, hoping I would share the concrete actions of the digital department in combating fraud.</p>

<p>In reality, fraud doesn’t just affect governance and economy, but its more severe consequence lies in the erosion of societal trust.</p>

<p>Should government units be impersonated by wrongdoers, crucial messages would fail to reach the public effectively; if e-commerce platforms are counterfeited, consumers would find it hard to trust, thereby reducing their willingness to purchase.</p>

<p>To combat fraud, the first step is to block the source of fraud and prevent personal information from being stolen. Consequently, the digital department is fully committed to promoting “Short Code SMS” and privacy-enhancing technologies, to assist industries in enhancing information security and reducing personal data leaks.</p>

<p>With numerous text messages received on mobile phones daily, how does one discern the genuine messages? The Ministry of Digital Affairs has designed a government-specific SMS short code for this very purpose. This set of numbers can only be used by government agencies for text messages. We anticipate its launch in the fourth quarter of this year, enabling everyone to distinguish it clearly and prevent counterfeit attempts by criminals.</p>

<p>Just like the anti-fraud hotline “165” and other government-exclusive numbers, they are easy to remember and can’t be altered. Upon determining this set of short codes, the digital department will liaise with telecom operators for preemptive technical checks.</p>

<p>Moreover, we are encouraging e-commerce partners to implement privacy-enhancing technologies, replacing the recipient’s contact number on the order with representative numbers and codes. Logistics personnel can contact the recipient by simply dialing the code, and the public can also contact logistics using this code. It’s not only convenient and memorable but can also prevent personal information leaks.</p>

<p>The second step in combating fraud is to prevent fraud at its end, even if personal information is unfortunately leaked, and to inhibit the flow of money. This is the “platform joint defense” implemented by the Digital Department.</p>

<p>The e-commerce anti-fraud collaborative platform was jointly established by the Ministry of Digital Affairs, industry associations, and Taiwan Network Information Center (TWNIC). Once an e-commerce partner identifies a fraudulent website and reports it to 165, the Taiwan Network Center can quickly halt the analysis of fraudulent domain names, minimizing the risk of domestic users being deceived, using the Public Association as a liaison.</p>

<p>The game point fraud collaborative platform was co-established by the Digital Department, the Procuratorate, the Executive Yuan’s Money Laundering Prevention Office, and the game point industry. It offers services like “game entry delay of forty-eight hours”, and “point anti-fraud lock card platform”. When the public discovers they have been deceived, they can lock it on the platform and return to the original store for a refund, thereby reducing losses.</p>

<p>From March this year until now, the card lock platform has successfully locked hundreds of transactions, and the number of reported incidents has been reduced from 1,500 per month to fewer than 100.</p>

<p>The public-private collaboration mechanism promoted by the Digital Department is also applied to virtual accounts. Should a bank discover an illegal virtual account, it can report to the Financial Supervisory Commission through the collaborative platform, and then the digital department will perform inspections according to law. For illegal cash flows, we cooperate with the Financial Supervisory Commission to establish a third-party payment inquiry system, helping relevant units obtain the necessary account information in the shortest possible time.</p>

<p>The goal of the digital department in combating fraud is to build a resilient protective net, not just fixing leaks at the end but also blocking them from the source. We will continue sharing specific methods and execution results, and we welcome readers to offer their opinions to improve our policy.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sheau-Tyng Peng</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Digital Industries" /><category term="Digital Service" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not just fixing leaks at the end but also blocking them from the source.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/hands-1947915_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/hands-1947915_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A phone call at 3,000 meters</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E4%B8%80%E9%80%9A%E6%A8%99%E9%AB%98%E4%B8%89%E5%8D%83%E5%85%AC%E5%B0%BA%E7%9A%84%E9%9B%BB%E8%A9%B1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A phone call at 3,000 meters" /><published>2023-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E4%B8%80%E9%80%9A%E6%A8%99%E9%AB%98%E4%B8%89%E5%8D%83%E5%85%AC%E5%B0%BA%E7%9A%84%E9%9B%BB%E8%A9%B1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E4%B8%80%E9%80%9A%E6%A8%99%E9%AB%98%E4%B8%89%E5%8D%83%E5%85%AC%E5%B0%BA%E7%9A%84%E9%9B%BB%E8%A9%B1/"><![CDATA[<p>In the ever-changing world of the internet, “instant reading” and “instant replies” are behaviors that many people take for granted. However, the colleagues in the Ministry of Digital Affairs (moda) must regularly make “one-minute phone calls” that can only be hung up at the last second.</p>

<p>This one-minute phone call is an important step to ensure the quality of communication everywhere. When the inspection staff arrives on site, the engineer will connect and capture the signal of the nearest base station, then connect to the operator’s system end, conduct a hundred reaction tests, and confirm that the network is smooth. The last phone call must last for one minute without interruption. Both the network and voice calls must meet the standard to pass the test.</p>

<p>Compared to the inspection completed within ten minutes, what is more time-consuming is to reach the inspection point. In May, colleagues from the moda and various telecommunications operators went to the 99 Mountain Villa on the top of Daba Peak, the Zhongba Mountain House at an altitude of 3,300 meters, and the Cuifeng Mountain House on Taiping Mountain to conduct forest communication measurements.</p>

<p>These long journeys are not only to provide hikers and tourists with fast and convenient communication quality, but also to enhance the digital resilience of various places and solve life problems through the internet.</p>

<p>For example, Taiwan is full of high mountains and vast territories. If there is an emergency medical need in the mountains, it is often restricted by transportation and affects medical treatment. Therefore, the moda supports telecommunications operators to develop 5G remote diagnosis and treatment platforms, which can transmit medical images in real time and allow specialist doctors to read them remotely.</p>

<p>Take the example of Ren’ai Township in Nantou County, where many tribes are deep in the mountains. The doctor of the health center can let the dermatologist see the patient’s lesions from a distance through video, making the diagnosis more accurate. This system has been used in twelve counties and cities and thirty-five townships, serving more than 30,000 people.</p>

<p>This method of “replacing roads with the internet” effectively meets life needs and is the original intention of the moda to continue promoting 5G applications. Therefore, we focus on “reducing costs”, “opening applications”, and “simplifying procedures” as the core, and officially open the application of 5G dedicated frequency dedicated network in June.</p>

<p>In order to encourage more industries to use it, the Administration for Digital Industries has formed a promotion group with thirteen public associations, including tourism, cultural performances, livelihood and manufacturing, etc., to propose industry blueprints for dedicated frequency dedicated network services and application solutions, and continue to participate in and support innovative applications.</p>

<p>For example, the immersive experience version of the Bell Ringing Drama Troupe “VALO Trilogy-Island” is supported by the Digital Department, telecommunications operators, and the Institute for Information Industry, allowing the four-story space of the National Theater to be filled with 5G signals and control 1,200 light source carriers. After the audience wears a 5G bracelet, they can be in the same fantasy world as the dancers and interact in real time.</p>

<p>This approach showcases the characteristics of 5G’s broad connectivity and low latency. The setup of more than a thousand signals not only ensures coverage in every corner of the venue but also significantly reduces the network connection delay time from an average of one second to 0.1 second. This allows the live performance and the audio-visual experience to be perfectly combined.</p>

<p>From one-minute phone calls to low-latency rates of 0.1 seconds, we continue to improve network quality. This allows 5G applications to become a helpful tool for everyday life and a new driving force for industries to move forward.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sheau-Tyng Peng</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Communications and Cyber Resilience" /><category term="Resource Management" /><category term="Digital Industries" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[5G remote diagnosis and treatment platforms can transmit medical images in real time.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/nature-g62a81da2f_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/nature-g62a81da2f_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Digital public infrastructure, shared by all</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%95%B8%E4%BD%8D%E5%85%AC%E5%85%B1%E5%BB%BA%E8%A8%AD-%E5%85%A8%E6%B0%91%E5%85%B1%E4%BA%AB/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Digital public infrastructure, shared by all" /><published>2023-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%95%B8%E4%BD%8D%E5%85%AC%E5%85%B1%E5%BB%BA%E8%A8%AD%EF%BC%8C%E5%85%A8%E6%B0%91%E5%85%B1%E4%BA%AB</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%95%B8%E4%BD%8D%E5%85%AC%E5%85%B1%E5%BB%BA%E8%A8%AD-%E5%85%A8%E6%B0%91%E5%85%B1%E4%BA%AB/"><![CDATA[<p>Alain Richard, Vice President of the French Senate, led the Senate Friendship Group to Taiwan to visit the Digital Department at the end of April. Members of the French political parties are most curious about how to design a system to smoothly promote digital services? I said that this is the result of long-term accumulation of inter-ministerial committees. The current “universal cash for all people” is the best example.</p>

<p>Public cash policy is based on triple- and quintuple-stimulus vouchers. Take the collection channel as an example. After the digital voucher is used up, you can choose to receive cash. At that time, only some banks’ automatic teller machines (ATM) supported it. This time we have promoted more banks to join, covering more than 80% of the country, serving more than 4 million people, and receiving 6,000 yuan directly at ATMs.</p>

<p>For friends who are inconvenient to collect in person, you can also register online on the official website, and let the cash be directly transferred to your account. The “children’s family epidemic prevention subsidy” system established in 2021 can not only ensure the guardianship relationship between the child and the recipient, but also allow the recipient to decide which account to remit to. Become the core structure of this popularization of gold.</p>

<p>Before the system was launched, the colleagues of the National Information Security Research Institute have comprehensively detected the weaknesses of information security, ensured that the entire transmission process is encrypted, and access to data must be authorized and recorded. Personal information is not only strictly protected, but will also be deleted one month after the completion of the project.</p>

<p>The targets of this issuance include foreign nationals holding permanent residence permits. Therefore, the Pufa Cash website is set up in a bilingual structure to avoid obstacles caused by language skills; Conforms to the AA level specification of the accessibility mark.</p>

<p>These practices not only make the website easier to use, but also take care of the needs of people with disabilities. Even if people access the system with their mobile phones during their busy commuting, they can still experience a clear, easy-to-understand and error-free usage process.</p>

<p>The smooth general distribution has come to an end, how to properly use this mechanism that combines identity verification, information flow, and cash flow in the future? We plan to expand this mechanism into “digital public construction” and provide it to government agencies at all levels for distribution operations; based on the spirit of public code, we will also provide value-added use of codes to various agencies to speed up system construction efficiency.</p>

<p>In addition, we will also import “T-Road cross-organization data transmission exclusive channel”, the whole process is encrypted with agency certificates, and will not be connected to external service network segments. Normally, the transmission interface is closed through T-Road, and the T-Road interface transmission can only be activated after the distribution operation is started and the competent authority and the personal information agency confirm the scope of access. In this way, agencies at all levels can ensure the security of personal information when performing distribution operations in the future.</p>

<p>A few days ago, the number of general cash recipients has exceeded 20 million, of which more than 9 million people have received online through the official website. The Ministry of Digital Affairs will continue to collaborate with various ministries to create more labor-saving and safe public programs, so that the public can obtain convenient services in multiple ways.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sheau-Tyng Peng</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Digital Service" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to properly use this mechanism that combines identity verification, information flow, and cash flow in the future?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/technology-5348129_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/technology-5348129_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Informed Data Governance, Rational Data Altruism</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E8%B3%87%E6%96%99%E6%B2%BB%E7%90%86%E6%9C%89%E6%99%BA-%E6%95%B8%E6%93%9A%E5%85%AC%E7%9B%8A%E6%9C%89%E7%90%86/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Informed Data Governance, Rational Data Altruism" /><published>2023-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E8%B3%87%E6%96%99%E6%B2%BB%E7%90%86%E6%9C%89%E6%99%BA-%E6%95%B8%E6%93%9A%E5%85%AC%E7%9B%8A%E6%9C%89%E7%90%86</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E8%B3%87%E6%96%99%E6%B2%BB%E7%90%86%E6%9C%89%E6%99%BA-%E6%95%B8%E6%93%9A%E5%85%AC%E7%9B%8A%E6%9C%89%E7%90%86/"><![CDATA[<p>This book is the crystallization of wisdom jointly created by academics and practitioners in the field of digital governance, following the publication of “Government Digital Transformation: An Essential Guide”. This time, the authors focus on “government data governance”, once again demonstrating their profound professional expertise.</p>

<p>If digital transformation is likened to the Industrial Revolution, data is the new energy driving the wheels of the times. Just as the development and utilization of energy are vital to the success of industries, data governance is the cornerstone of digital transformation.</p>

<p>Today, with the popularization of audiovisual and language models, businesses ranging from translation, customer service, marketing, and content creation are all impacted by generative technologies. Just like advancement of refining technology has liberated fossil fuels from primitive uses such as lighting and heating — not only producing powerful propulsion for land, sea, and air vehicles but also generating countless plastic products, permeating every aspect of food, clothing, housing, transportation, education, and entertainment — the prevalence of foundation models spurs global investment in data applications, unleashing boundless creativity.</p>

<p>However, just as petrochemical products have triggered climate crises and ecological disasters, leading to the pursuit of clean energy as a century-long challenge, foundation models are closely related to large datasets from training to application. If there is no foundation for proper governance, cyber-ecological disasters are imminent, with deepfake scams being just the tip of the iceberg.</p>

<p>Fortunately, the international community is paying close attention to governance issues, expecting legal, ethical, and technological advancements to proceed hand in hand. At the G7 Digital and Technology Ministers’ Meeting held in Japan in late April, a joint statement was issued, pledging to promote “human-centered” principles to maximize benefits for all and oppose misuse and abuse that undermines democracy, freedom, and human rights. The statement echoes the spirit of the “Declaration of the Summit for Democracy” and the “Declaration for the Future of Internet”, pointing out that a “Data Free Flow with Trust (DFFT)” mechanism is the top priority for cross-border collaboration.</p>

<p>In other words, in the face of rapidly developing technologies such as foundation models, even if there are concerns about harms to human rights and democratic values, “free flow” remains the primary value of cross-border data governance, rather than building isolated strongholds or resorting to government regulation to reject data flow, turning advanced countries into “prohibition-first” countries.</p>

<p>The five principles put forward in the statement — “rule of law”, “due process”, “democracy”, “respect for human rights” and “harnessing the opportunities of innovation” — can be summed up as “human centric”, firmly defending the value and protection of individuals as data subjects. Just like the well-known fable, if governments cannot sincerely face the lost iron axe, they will not be rewarded with golden and silver axes.</p>

<p>The Ministry of Digital Affairs was established in response to public expectations, with the mission of “government digital services, data governance, and open data”. As a supplement to legal and ethical norms, we promote Privacy Enhancing Technologies (PETs) and actively assist e-commerce and logistics companies in adopting them to reduce the risk of personal data breaches.</p>

<p>Observing international trends, the European Union recently advocated privacy-enhancing processing, proactively transforming high-value data into non-personal data, promoting applications across various sectors for public benefit.</p>

<p>In Taiwan, public-benefit applications such as climate and environment, disaster prevention and rescue, transportation, health care, energy management, and social assistance all have corresponding “high-value” topics on the data.gov.tw platform, inspiring endless innovative solutions. Over the past decade, the platform has attracted 113 million views and over 19 million downloads, and through events like the “Presidential Hackathon”, it inspired a myriad of practical co-creations.</p>

<p>In other words, the “oil analogy” mentioned in this book may only be half right; oil and minerals are rival goods, but data is quite the opposite, possessing “non-exclusivity” and “non-competitiveness”. Under a governance environment built on sound legal systems and privacy-enhancing technologies, data can exhibit “anti-rival good” characteristics: the more it is shared, the greater its value, contributing to both individuals and the world.</p>

<p>That is to say, only in an environment of free flow with trust can the “data altruism” concept proposed by the European Union’s Data Governance Act (DGA) be realized: data holders voluntarily provide data to drive societal development and improve public service quality.</p>

<p>As foundation models become popular, the vision of “data democratization” in Chapter 10 of this book is about to be realized, with everyone expected to become a producer and user, and “data governance” becoming a core issue in digital development. The publication of this book will undoubtedly guide all sectors to achieve informed and rational data governance. Only by pooling the collective intelligence can we establish mutual connections, foster virtuous collaborations toward the common good, and realize “data altruism” in a rational and principled fashion. It is my pleasure to write this foreword.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Plural Innovation" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA["Data Free Flow with Trust" is the top priority for cross-border collaboration.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/binary-ga626d4a1f_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/binary-ga626d4a1f_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ten years of open data, opening up an infinite future</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%8D%81%E5%B9%B4%E9%96%8B%E6%94%BE%E8%B3%87%E6%96%99-%E9%96%8B%E5%95%9F%E7%84%A1%E9%99%90%E6%9C%AA%E4%BE%86/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ten years of open data, opening up an infinite future" /><published>2023-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%8D%81%E5%B9%B4%E9%96%8B%E6%94%BE%E8%B3%87%E6%96%99-%E9%96%8B%E5%95%9F%E7%84%A1%E9%99%90%E6%9C%AA%E4%BE%86</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%8D%81%E5%B9%B4%E9%96%8B%E6%94%BE%E8%B3%87%E6%96%99-%E9%96%8B%E5%95%9F%E7%84%A1%E9%99%90%E6%9C%AA%E4%BE%86/"><![CDATA[<p>April of this year marks a significant milestone in Taiwan’s development of open data, celebrating the 10th anniversary of the “Government Open Data Platform.” Today, the platform has opened access to more than 55,000 datasets, boasting over 110 million views and 19 million downloads.</p>

<p>Over the years, numerous creative applications that address social issues have emerged from the foundation of open data. For example, innovative ideas, such as an irrigation system that combines rainwater warnings and a smart system designed to help farmers and fishermen cultivate clams, have been proposed by contestants in data application competitions in recent years.</p>

<p>The key to the success of these ideas lies in the continuous release of various types of high impact data by government agencies.</p>

<p>In the past, high impact data with significant public value, such as meteorological observations and disaster relief resources, often faced legal and computational constraints, preventing their easy release. Over the past decade, the government has persevered in overcoming these challenges to provide data for public use.</p>

<p>For instance, the Central Weather Bureau’s “Meteorological Resources Innovation Application Plan,” announced in 2022, opened up access to high-precision meteorological data and resources for legal entities and businesses. This not only improves the accuracy of weather forecasts but also enables the development of targeted meteorological and ocean current analyses for industries like fisheries and shipping.</p>

<p>This case study demonstrates the potential for high-value application data to connect different industries and professions. After soliciting opinions from various ministries and the public, the Digital Ministry has established a “High Application Value Thematic Area” on the Government Open Data Platform.</p>

<p>Departing from the previous classification based on industry or agency, we now categorize data based on “themes” according to social value and content. Initially, six data sets were classified: climate and environment, disaster prevention and rescue, transportation, health and medical care, energy management, and social assistance. Theme-based planning not only aids in data search but also reveals the connections between different data sets, stimulating further collaboration.</p>

<p>For example, the “climate and environment” dataset can contribute to the net-zero transition. The goal of “net-zero” is to minimize human-induced greenhouse gas emissions while offsetting them through negative emissions technologies and forest carbon sinks. In line with the 2021 United Nations Glasgow Climate Agreement, Taiwan proposed a “2050 Net-Zero Emissions Pathway” in March last year and officially implemented the “Climate Change Response Act” this year.</p>

<p>The theme of this year’s Presidential Hackathon International Track, “#FreeTheFuture: Open, Digital &amp; Green,” combines democratic communication, data application, and net-zero carbon emissions, presenting an excellent opportunity for interdisciplinary data sharing and use.</p>

<p>Earth’s natural resources, often depleted due to human over-exploitation, are considered competitive assets, leaving less for future generations. In contrast, open data serves as an “anti-rival good,” where sharing increases its value and contributes to both individuals and the world.</p>

<p>The Digital Ministry will continue to promote the opening and application of data for public good, assisting in the sustainable use of scarce global resources, and welcoming more friends to join our ranks.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sheau-Tyng Peng</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Plural Innovation" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data for public good assists the sustainable use of scarce global resources.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/earth-gab4518d56_1920.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/earth-gab4518d56_1920.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Summit for Democracy: Shaping emerging technologies to align with human rights and democratic principles</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%B0%91%E4%B8%BB%E5%B3%B0%E6%9C%83-%E5%BD%A2%E5%A1%91%E6%96%B0%E8%88%88%E7%A7%91%E6%8A%80%E4%BB%A5%E7%A2%BA%E4%BF%9D%E5%B0%8A%E9%87%8D%E4%BA%BA%E6%AC%8A%E8%88%87%E6%B0%91%E4%B8%BB%E5%8E%9F%E5%89%87/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Summit for Democracy: Shaping emerging technologies to align with human rights and democratic principles" /><published>2023-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%B0%91%E4%B8%BB%E5%B3%B0%E6%9C%83-%E5%BD%A2%E5%A1%91%E6%96%B0%E8%88%88%E7%A7%91%E6%8A%80%E4%BB%A5%E7%A2%BA%E4%BF%9D%E5%B0%8A%E9%87%8D%E4%BA%BA%E6%AC%8A%E8%88%87%E6%B0%91%E4%B8%BB%E5%8E%9F%E5%89%87</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%B0%91%E4%B8%BB%E5%B3%B0%E6%9C%83-%E5%BD%A2%E5%A1%91%E6%96%B0%E8%88%88%E7%A7%91%E6%8A%80%E4%BB%A5%E7%A2%BA%E4%BF%9D%E5%B0%8A%E9%87%8D%E4%BA%BA%E6%AC%8A%E8%88%87%E6%B0%91%E4%B8%BB%E5%8E%9F%E5%89%87/"><![CDATA[<p>Good local time, everyone. I’m Audrey Tang, Taiwan’s digital minister.</p>

<p>It is a genuine honor to participate in the second Summit for Democracy. I will share Taiwan’s experiences in tackling common challenges facing our free and open societies and how emerging technologies strengthen human rights and democratic principles.</p>

<p>Since the inaugural Summit for Democracy in December 2021, the world has fundamentally changed. Russia’s illegal and unprovoked war of aggression against Ukraine has sent shockwaves throughout the international community.</p>

<p>As democracies adapt to this reality, Taiwan shines brightly as a trustworthy and most reliable partner in promoting digital resilience. During the darkest days of COVID-19, our industries rose to the challenge, becoming a potent producer of essential medical supplies. Our civic technology supported the emergence of the Taiwan Can Help model in a global counter-pandemic coalition.</p>

<p>Based on this rock-solid foundation of collaboration, I signed the Declaration for the Future of the Internet in 2022, along with 60 partner countries. The declaration cemented our shared values and
deepened our commitment to democratic allies, paving the way to free the future in the digital realm together.</p>

<p>At the heart of this vision is the Ministry of Digital Affairs (moda), and its objective of “digital resilience for all.” This comprises three levels: Emergency, industrial, and societal resilience.</p>

<p>Emergency resilience impels us to effectively respond to various crises, including cyberattacks and natural disasters. Recent incidents, such as those during the former U.S. House Speaker Nancy Pelosi’s historic visit to Taiwan, unsuccessfully attempted to undermine public trust in our democratic system.</p>

<p>To counter emerging threats, including AI-powered interactive deep fakes, we are consolidating public and private cybersecurity capabilities,
implementing zero-trust principles, and conducting exercises to ensure the seamless operation of critical infrastructure during emergencies.</p>

<p>Starting this year, we’re integrating new satellite providers, enabling multiple networks to reinforce one another across land, sea, and air in times of crisis. The moda website uses IPFS, an emerging technology
for censorship resistance, so everyone can donate connectivity to back us up, while also supporting journalists in autocracies so their reportage remains tamper-free.</p>

<p>Industrial resilience is our commitment to facilitating digital transformation across all sectors while fostering a robust ecosystem. Taiwan possesses a highly advanced IT industry with a world-class semiconductor supply chain and a wealth of experience neutralizing cyberthreats. With global standards such as SEMI E187, we
elevate the Made in Taiwan brand to represent a guarantee of integrity and a solid shield to our democratic partners.</p>

<p>Societal resilience focuses on empowering our civil society by connecting to the democracy network. The moda initiated the Digital News Co-prosperity dialogues with global platforms and brought together the Ministry of Culture, National Communications Commission, and Fair Trade Commission to explore ways of fostering mutually beneficial cooperation with Taiwan’s print, broadcast, and digital journalists.</p>

<p>We believe that accurate news reporting is the bedrock of democracy, and digital competence requires a well-informed and discerning citizenry. In the face of authoritarian expansionism, democracies must confront formidable challenges undermining the delicate equilibrium between societal well-being and individual freedoms. Our efforts must go beyond devising protective measures — we’re envisioning a trajectory embracing the triad of participation, progress, and safety through the power of collective intelligence.</p>

<p>This approach is embodied in the moda’s overarching vision: Plurality, or collaborative diversity. When people from all walks of life can form
digital public spaces together, we can empower the voices reaching across ideological divides and uncover our shared values in plain sight.</p>

<p>As we navigate uncharted waters, I urge you to stand with Taiwan in the pursuit of digital resilience. We must tap into our collective intelligence, innovation, and determination to effect real and lasting change. Let’s embark on this journey and show the world the indomitable spirit of democracy — together.</p>

<p>Thank you. Live long and … prosper.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/e0iHsN0XoWs" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sheau-Tyng Peng</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Digital Resilience" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Empower the voices reaching across ideological divides and uncover our shared values in plain sight.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/20230330.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/20230330.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>