<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-02-11T17:13:10+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/feed.xml</id><author><name>PDIS</name></author><entry><title type="html">The era of password-free login has arrived</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E4%B8%80%E7%B5%84%E5%B8%B3%E8%99%9F%E8%B5%B0%E9%81%8D%E7%B6%B2%E8%B7%AF%E7%9A%84%E6%99%82%E4%BB%A3%E4%BE%86%E4%BA%86/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The era of password-free login has arrived" /><published>2023-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E4%B8%80%E7%B5%84%E5%B8%B3%E8%99%9F%E8%B5%B0%E9%81%8D%E7%B6%B2%E8%B7%AF%E7%9A%84%E6%99%82%E4%BB%A3%E4%BE%86%E4%BA%86</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E4%B8%80%E7%B5%84%E5%B8%B3%E8%99%9F%E8%B5%B0%E9%81%8D%E7%B6%B2%E8%B7%AF%E7%9A%84%E6%99%82%E4%BB%A3%E4%BE%86%E4%BA%86/"><![CDATA[<p>At the beginning of the new year, I would like to share a piece of good news with you: since January this year, the Digital Development Department has officially become a member of the international standards organization W3C (World Wide Web Consortium). It not only breaks through the predicament of only being able to join international organizations as a civilian, but also a milestone in the expansion of the Plurality.</p>

<p>At the same time, the Ministry of Digital Technology has also joined the FIDO Alliance, which develops and promotes safe and convenient identification standards, becoming the second Taiwan government unit member after joining the Ministry of the Interior in 2021.</p>

<p>Thanks to the standards set by W3C, websites can be properly displayed on every device, be it a phone, tablet, or computer. In other words, without these standards, even if you have the device, you may not be able to read the website’s content. This means no more seamless streaming, online shopping, or any activity through websites. Its importance to the world is obvious.</p>

<p>However, if you want to further interact with other people through the website, such as making videos and publishing articles, you almost always need to register and upload information first. However, account information on a single website often cannot be shared and circulated among different platforms. This not only leads to the monopoly of a few large cross-border platforms, but also limits everyone’s independent right to use data.</p>

<p>Therefore, many communities have developed their own “code portability” solutions, so that everyone can freely choose the most suitable creative environment, fully exercise their data rights, and create more exciting works together. However, there must be a global technical specification to make these solutions truly interoperable with each other.</p>

<p>So in July 2022, W3C launched a brand-new decentralized identity verification standard (DIDs), allowing us to see the dawn of a new generation of digital services. This set of standards allows everyone to directly verify each other’s identities without going through an intermediary service.</p>

<p>We might as well think of this identity mark as an “Internet Passport”. This passport allows everyone to carry their own digital assets; whether it is social posts, photos or videos, it is no longer the cross-border platform that controls these contents, but returns to each creator himself.</p>

<p>If W3C proposes a set of standards for verifying passports, allowing everyone to have their own digital identities; then the FIDO Alliance is responsible for ensuring the security of this passport.</p>

<p>The FIDO Alliance, established in 2013, is an international non-profit organization jointly established by the information industry. Their original intention is to solve the problem of authentication identity. In the past, when logging in to website services, you had to type in your password, which was not only difficult to save, but also faced risks such as account theft and identity fraudulent use.</p>

<p>Therefore, the FIDO Alliance formulated the standard of “password-free login”, and developed various passports for W3C, plus security locks and keys. In this way, everyone can use their passports more safely to roam in the Internet space.</p>

<p>As a member of two major international organizations, the Ministry of Digital Affairs will participate in the formulation of standards according to the needs of all walks of life in Taiwan, and synchronize with the world, and immediately introduce these emerging standards into government agencies, civil society and the industry to practice Plurality – collaborative diversity.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sheau-Tyng Peng</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Democracy Network" /><category term="Digital Industries" /><category term="Cyber Security" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Participate in the formulation of standards and interoperate with the world.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/blockchain-3513216_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/blockchain-3513216_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Send noodle online cloud</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E9%80%81%E9%BA%B5%E7%B7%9A%E4%B8%8A%E9%9B%B2%E7%AB%AF/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Send noodle online cloud" /><published>2022-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E9%80%81%E9%BA%B5%E7%B7%9A%E4%B8%8A%E9%9B%B2%E7%AB%AF</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E9%80%81%E9%BA%B5%E7%B7%9A%E4%B8%8A%E9%9B%B2%E7%AB%AF/"><![CDATA[<p>A few days ago, my colleagues from the Industrial Development Administration and I went to the oil depot in Banqiao to learn about the application of the <a href="https://www.tcloud.gov.tw/">Taiwan Cloud Market</a> platform . The store has been in business for 36 years. From roadside stalls to storefronts, it is already a time-honored snack bar in Banqiao. The steaming noodles and the sweet and plump oysters are impressive.</p>

<p>The boss said that they usually start preparing materials at six o’clock in the morning, and then open the store from nine thirty in the morning until seven o’clock in the evening. Even if there is an endless stream of customers, the well-trained clerks keep the queue from stagnating. From ordering to checkout, the meal can be served in an average of five minutes.</p>

<p>However, at the same time, the clerks are still overwhelmed with various customized needs such as on-site ordering and delivery, answering reservation calls, confirming takeaway orders, and “no coriander”. Recording and verbal transmission using only pen and paper is time-consuming and error-prone.</p>

<p>This problem has found an effective solution through the “Taiwan Cloud Market” platform promoted by the Digital Industry Agency of the Ministry of Digital Affairs.</p>

<p>“Taiwan Cloud Bazaar” integrates cross-agency processes such as the Ministry of Finance, the Ministry of the Interior, and the Ministry of Economic Affairs, and selects various cloud tools and services suitable for small and medium-sized enterprises into a single platform.</p>

<p>As long as it meets the certification standards of small and medium-sized enterprises, or is a profit-making enterprise with tax registration, in just ten minutes, all procedures such as application, review and signing can be completed on the cloud market website, and the digital transformation plan can be directly purchased. You can also get up to 30,000 yuan in digital point subsidies. If you don’t know how to choose the right solution, there are also expert consultants online to provide assistance.</p>

<p>Through the cloud market, Youkukou Noodle Shop adopts the “Quicker Line Ordering Customer Service System” to provide customers with 24-hour online ordering and online payment.</p>

<p>Through digital operation, the clerk no longer needs to answer the phone, and the verbal confirmation time of about three minutes is eliminated for each order. Moreover, because of the online ordering system, it has reached a wider customer base and increased the consumption of online group buying, and the average unit price of each customer has increased by at least two times. In addition, through data collection, it is also helpful for raw material management, making the purchase cost more accurate.</p>

<p>From the story of Youkukou noodle shop, we can see that the cloud service with open subscription system and transferable data is an important digital transformation tool for SME partners. Therefore, in addition to helping more business partners introduce cloud solutions through the cloud market, we also encourage service providers to continue to innovate through the “Digital Cloud Service Thematic R&amp;D Subsidy Program” and develop simple and easy-to-use cloud solutions for all walks of life. plan.</p>

<p>At present, “Taiwan Cloud Market” has collected 15 types of cloud solutions such as online store opening, marketing promotion, remote office, enterprise management, customer service, and market analysis. As of November this year, there have been more than 15 cloud solutions Thirty-six thousand companies use it.</p>

<p>All walks of life have different operating objectives. The Digital Department continues to assist everyone in finding suitable digital tools and cloud services, so that all kinds of carefully crafted services and products can be delivered to customers easily and simply.</p>]]></content><author><name>唐鳳、彭筱婷</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="數位產業" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA["Taiwan Cloud Marketplace" has been used by more than 36,000 companies.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/digitization-7580781_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/digitization-7580781_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Made in Taiwan Reliable and Reliable</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E8%87%BA%E7%81%A3%E8%A3%BD%E9%80%A0-%E4%BF%A1%E8%B3%B4%E5%8F%AF%E9%9D%A0/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Made in Taiwan Reliable and Reliable" /><published>2022-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E8%87%BA%E7%81%A3%E8%A3%BD%E9%80%A0-%E4%BF%A1%E8%B3%B4%E5%8F%AF%E9%9D%A0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E8%87%BA%E7%81%A3%E8%A3%BD%E9%80%A0-%E4%BF%A1%E8%B3%B4%E5%8F%AF%E9%9D%A0/"><![CDATA[<p>A while ago, FCC Commissioner Brendan Carr visited Taiwan for the first time. When visiting the Ministry of Digital Technology, he pointed out that Taiwan is a reliable economic and national security partner, and he very much looks forward to the deepening of cooperation between the two sides in matters related to information security.</p>

<p>Commissioner Karl’s statement has its own reasons. Taiwan has become the world leader in semiconductor and information and communication manufacturing, and has the most complete industrial supply chain in the world. And we are at the forefront of overseas cyber attacks, and we have rich practical experience in information security.</p>

<p>With the recent rapid changes in the international situation, governments of various countries are paying more and more attention to the security risks of technology products. For example, the United Kingdom announced that it will completely remove Huawei’s 5G products by 2027. Therefore, the digital department will integrate “industrial information security” and “information security industry” to create a reliable supply chain.</p>

<p>In terms of strengthening industrial information security, in January this year, the world’s first semiconductor information security standard “SEMI E187” jointly created by Taiwan’s industry, government, academia and research circles was officially released. Is the device secure. In order to help more operators to use it, practical operation guidelines were also released in October to guide the industry in evaluating whether the product complies with the regulations.</p>

<p>In addition, in the past, Chinese manufacturers could only send chips to foreign laboratories for safety testing. If the inspection failed, the industry had to modify the product before sending it for inspection, resulting in high costs.</p>

<p>Now, the “Chip Security Joint Testing Laboratory” is jointly established by the Ministry of Digital Industry, the academic community and the industry, providing local testing for the industry to enter the international market at a lower cost and faster.</p>

<p>From these experiences, it can be seen that information security is already a necessary investment in semiconductors and even all walks of life; Taiwan began to promote the “six core strategic industries” two years ago, including the excellent information security industry.</p>

<p>In recent years, Taiwan’s new information security enterprises have also made significant progress in “quality” and “quantity”. Up to now, 28 information security innovations have been established, among which Laiyi Digital and Boou Technology have also won the In the past two years, he has won the first prize in the field of network security of SelectUSA, an investment summit in the United States.</p>

<p>As a digital “coach” for various industries, the Ministry of Digital Industry has also built Taiwan’s first information security practice base “Shalun Information Security Service Base” to help strengthen industrial information security and promote the information security industry.</p>

<p>The information security base simulated and designed twelve sets of attack scenarios based on information security incidents at home and abroad. In response to these scenarios, we have also cooperated with domestic information security companies to develop defensive countermeasures. The team can not only use it to participate in the actual test, grasp the advantages and disadvantages of their own products, but also learn more about suitable solutions.</p>

<p>In other words, the information security service base is not only a training ground for information security manufacturers, but also a platform for matching supply and demand and gathering business opportunities in the information security industry.</p>

<p>Made in Taiwan (MIT) has always been a quality assurance. Today, T not only represents Taiwan, but also means trustworthiness. By strengthening industrial information security and developing the information security industry, the Digital Division will let the world see: “Made in Taiwan means trust and reliability.”</p>]]></content><author><name>唐鳳、彭筱婷</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="數位產業" /><category term="資通安全" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[MIT has always been a guarantee of quality. Today, T is more trustworthy (Trustworthiness).]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/hands-1947915_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/hands-1947915_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Idea loose, build infinite future</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E9%BB%9E%E5%AD%90%E6%9D%BE-%E6%89%93%E9%80%A0%E7%84%A1%E9%99%90%E6%9C%AA%E4%BE%86/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Idea loose, build infinite future" /><published>2022-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E9%BB%9E%E5%AD%90%E6%9D%BE,%E6%89%93%E9%80%A0%E7%84%A1%E9%99%90%E6%9C%AA%E4%BE%86</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E9%BB%9E%E5%AD%90%E6%9D%BE-%E6%89%93%E9%80%A0%E7%84%A1%E9%99%90%E6%9C%AA%E4%BE%86/"><![CDATA[<p>The hashtag for the Ministry of Digital Development, why #FreeTheFuture?</p>

<p>Decades ago, the well-known science fiction writer William Gibson (William Gibson) experienced the emerging virtual reality (VR) technology and expressed his feelings: “The future has come, but it is not evenly distributed.” At that time VR is not yet mature enough to be a part of everyday life, but the experience has given him a glimpse into the future.</p>

<p>Free the Future means that the future has infinite possibilities, because the digital world can not only break the limitation of time and space, but also allow us to communicate and co-create with all kinds of people, so that imaginary things can become reality.</p>

<p>In the past few years, Taiwan has achieved many fruitful results of national cooperation. For example, for friends at home and abroad who are interested in improving government digital services, the “Presidents Cup Hackathon” provides a place to realize good ideas, and has now become a milestone in Taiwan’s public innovation.</p>

<p>The Digital Development Department has been planning since the preparatory period. Through co-creation by the whole people, the physical interpersonal network will be further expanded into a multiverse of “co-presence, code-carrying interoperability”. “Idea Pine” hopes to take a step towards the future through the unlimited imagination of the whole people.</p>

<p>In view of the fact that 6G technology will mature around 2040, related applications will shape the future life. The future is originally formed by everyone’s imagination,</p>

<p>Therefore, this year’s first Ideas Song takes “WeWe Futures: 2040 Multiverse (Plurality)” as the theme, open to individual and group submissions, and also provides virtual and real The inclusive and immersive performance allows all people to discuss our expectations for 2040 through personal participation.</p>

<p>How is IdeaThon different from other hackathons? In the past, the Presidents Cup Hackathon was open to citizens to make wishes, and several experts proposed solutions and implemented them on the ground; Ideasong welcomed social co-creation and invited all citizens to explore the possibility of the future together.</p>

<p>In other words, Ideasong is completely open to all kinds of submission forms. On the basis of hackathons, it breaks away from the achievements of website applications in the past, and further expands the thinking and actions of the participation of the whole people.</p>

<p>“Future News” individual competition, all individuals are welcome to create events or reports that may happen in 2040, not limited to video, text or multimedia; “Future Prototype” team competition encourages the development of design concepts for 2040, including tangible Space commodities, intangible service mechanisms, or living entities. As long as you are shortlisted, you will receive interdisciplinary expert guidance, and through the assistance of extended reality technology, you will produce a prototype of the concept.</p>

<p>In 2015, after experiencing VR again, Gibson said: “They did it!” The novelist who had already described the digital world before the Internet was popular, saw the future he described actually come.</p>

<p>No one can accurately predict the future, but everyone can bring the outline of the future to the present through imagination and creation, and then realize it through co-creation. This is the original intention of Ideasong, and also the expectation of the Digital Department: co-creation by all people, so that the future comes through everyone.</p>]]></content><author><name>唐鳳、彭筱婷</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="數位策略" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Co-creation by the whole people, let the future come through everyone.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/light-bulbs-1407610_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/light-bulbs-1407610_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What is a multiverse?</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E4%BB%80%E9%BA%BC%E6%98%AF%E5%A4%9A%E5%85%83%E5%AE%87%E5%AE%99/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is a multiverse?" /><published>2022-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E4%BB%80%E9%BA%BC%E6%98%AF%E5%A4%9A%E5%85%83%E5%AE%87%E5%AE%99</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E4%BB%80%E9%BA%BC%E6%98%AF%E5%A4%9A%E5%85%83%E5%AE%87%E5%AE%99/"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, many friends are very curious about the “Multiverse Division” of the Digital Development Department. Is it like the plots that have appeared in science fiction works, where there are multiple completely different societies on different timelines? And is the multiverse science going to “govern” these different societies?</p>

<p>This is indeed quite creative thinking. However, just as the Digital Development Department does not conduct supervision business, the Multiverse Division is not the “Time Variation Administration” in the comics. The existence of this section is to allow the “metaverse” (metaverse) to communicate with each other and create new applications freely.</p>

<p>The currently known Metaverse is extended through AR (augmented reality), VR (virtual reality) and other digital technologies, allowing people to appear as their own avatars in a world constructed in a virtual environment. However, the current virtual world can only interact within a specific digital platform, which virtually limits the possibility of innovation.</p>

<p>How to break the restriction and communicate directly? In fact, in our lives, the practice of multiverses has been practically applied everywhere.</p>

<p>Mobile phone number is a good example. Not only can you call across telecommunication providers, but you can also “carry codes” at any time to transfer your original mobile phone number to the telecommunication provider you want to use. The advantage of this is that everyone has more choices. You don’t need to re-register your phone number and rebuild all your contact information, and you can freely choose your preferred service.</p>

<p>However, the current large-scale cross-border digital platforms are not like this, and accounts are limited to use within the platform. Just like a mobile phone, it only has the function of calling within the network, and cannot call the numbers of other telecom operators. If you want to connect with others through different platforms, you must create an account on each platform. It’s like everyone has to print several business cards, and the information on each business card cannot be updated synchronously.</p>

<p>Such restrictions virtually stifle the possibility of innovation. Because all accounts must be approved by the platform, they can only be shared on a single platform. Moreover, the platform side controls all interactive data under each account, which poses risks to privacy and information security.</p>

<p>If you want to freely connect and interact with other people without being influenced by the middle platform, you can use the “end-to-end encryption” method. That is, only the endpoints actually participating can see each other’s messages, and the interaction will not be intercepted and recorded. This is the core concept of the “multiverse”: everyone can freely choose different channels to connect to each other securely.</p>

<p>What can multiverse science do? In fact, there are precedents to follow. More than ten years ago, instant messages in the Internet world could communicate with each other across platforms. E-mail is one of the earliest interoperable applications, and everyone can freely send to mailboxes in other domains.</p>

<p>Use appropriate tools to communicate with each other, and then build consensus and spread innovation. This is the vision of the “Future Internet Manifesto”, which is the “multiverse” that Taiwan is developing.</p>

<p>Through a point-to-point, multi-center, and decentralized architecture, the Digital Development Department will continue to use the concept of interoperability to promote innovative applications that reflect local needs, creating an infinite future for Taiwan and the world.</p>]]></content><author><name>唐鳳、彭筱婷</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="民主網絡" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everyone can freely choose different channels to connect with each other securely.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/team-4200837_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/team-4200837_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Moda begins with Public Code</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%95%B8%E4%BD%8D%E9%83%A8%E5%BE%9E%E5%B0%8E%E5%85%A5%E5%85%AC%E5%85%B1%E7%A8%8B%E5%BC%8F%E9%96%8B%E5%A7%8B/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Moda begins with Public Code" /><published>2022-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%95%B8%E4%BD%8D%E9%83%A8%E5%BE%9E%E5%B0%8E%E5%85%A5%E5%85%AC%E5%85%B1%E7%A8%8B%E5%BC%8F%E9%96%8B%E5%A7%8B</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%95%B8%E4%BD%8D%E9%83%A8%E5%BE%9E%E5%B0%8E%E5%85%A5%E5%85%AC%E5%85%B1%E7%A8%8B%E5%BC%8F%E9%96%8B%E5%A7%8B/"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, Taiwan has faced a lot of foreign interference. On August 2 alone, the websites of government agencies were attacked by hackers. In terms of distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) traffic, it was 23 times higher than the previous record of traffic volume in a single day.</p>

<p>Under such high-density pressure, it is fortunate that the information security personnel of various agencies can adjust the structure and respond quickly. This also confirms the importance of “digital resilience”.</p>

<p>Next, we will continue to strengthen our physical fitness. Regarding the results of the implementation of open licensing in recent years, the Ministry of Digital Development will use the “public code” as the core to further strengthen digital resilience.</p>

<p>Why is the key to public programs? In the past, free software, which was freely used and collaborative, started the “open source” movement and encouraged developers to publish code.</p>

<p>But only government agencies, due to organizational and regulatory constraints, make it difficult to import free software; the system of each unit often hinders interoperability due to different specifications. If there is a problem, it is difficult for other departments to immediately support.</p>

<p>In order to completely reverse the deadlock and expand social and economic development with a digital base, the European Free Software Foundation (FSFE) has initiated the “public money, public code” movement since 2017, advocating “ The system programs established by the government should be fully disclosed, with clear guidelines and specifications.”</p>

<p>For example, to improve the digital resilience of the official website of the government, we can make good use of public programs, deploy a decentralized structure, and create a “plurality” of services. Even if a certain part is attacked, the security and availability of the system can still be maintained through the joint defense mechanism.</p>

<p>The most important transnational case in recent years, X-Road, is a system jointly maintained by the governments of Estonia, Finland and Iceland. Governments of all countries can use it freely in their own countries, such as applying for subsidies, renewing driver’s licenses, etc. Once problems are found, they can immediately make corrections and feed them back to the system, so that other units can update them synchronously.</p>

<p>As can be seen from X-Road, public programs are like transnational railways. Countries share the same tracks, schedules, and even carriage specifications, while railway tracks and related facilities in different countries are maintained and operated by that country. If one of the countries fixes track problems or develops new parts, it will also inform other countries to share experience and improve quality.</p>

<p>X-Road has created a milestone in the government’s digital practice, showing us that public programs are not only a protective net for information security, but also have the opportunity to create a democratic ecology of symbiosis, sharing and co-creation.</p>

<p>For this reason, I also proposed to join CC0 (public domain contribution, refers to free software that is not restricted by copyright), and join the international <a href="https://standard.publiccode.net/">Public Code Standard</a>. In this way, as long as the materials and content authorized by CC0 are used, they have the opportunity to enter the digital infrastructure of governments at all levels.</p>

<p>In the preparatory stage, the Digital Development Department has been exploring with the service providers how to introduce the concept of public programs. In the future, our content and programs will gradually adopt CC0 authorization and release them to the public domain, so as to share the foundation of resilience with democratic partners and create a model of digital governance.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sheau-Tyng Peng</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Open Government" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As you can see from X-Road, public code are like cross-country railways.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/rails-gb4c806ad8_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/rails-gb4c806ad8_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Esports Policy Resume</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/project/esports/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Esports Policy Resume" /><published>2022-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/project/esports</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/project/esports/"><![CDATA[<p>The game market research agency NEWZOO released a special article on the “2021 Global E-sports and Live Streaming Market Report” in March 2021. According to the report, the global e-sports market revenue will increase from $947.1 million last year to $1.084 billion, With an annual growth rate of 14.5%, it can be seen that the e-sports industry will be an emerging industry just around the corner.</p>

<p>However, before 2017, in order to develop the prospects of e-sports talents in the e-sports business, and to carry out Taiwan e-sports-related matters, including professional courses, alternative service for players, and related regulations, a series of inter-departmental meetings were held. There will be a business rights and responsibility coordination meeting on how to create a suitable environment for e-sports talents.</p>

<p>In the process, we adhered to the "innovative" meeting method within the "Open Government" of the Office, and applied and opened up the four core principles of the government - "transparency", "participation", "responsibility", and "containment". At the very beginning, take stock of the viewpoints of stakeholders (e-sports players, NGOs, government ministries, members of the Legislative Yuan, schools, etc.), and ensure that every discussion has a record. This is the first demonstration of transparency. Verbatim and public, became the main niche of open government.</p>

<p>Next, let the verbatim draft of the discussion process in the open meeting, through the process of formal policy discussion, through digital dialogue, bring the feasible and constructive opinions of netizens on the Internet back to the reference during the discussion process , which not only sets the best example for the new discussion methods of "participation", "responsibility", and "accommodation", but also effectively tracks the unresolved issues before, making the progress of each time open online, which really brings the mutual trust between the government and the people closer. Set up a more stable pace of discussion in the future.</p>

<p><a href="https://pdis-tw.kumu.io/電子競技政策履歷?token=dG0IhKBVoh7dj0BB" target="_blank">Policy History</a></p>

<p><a href="https://pdis-tw.kumu.io/電子競技政策履歷?token=dG0IhKBVoh7dj0BB" target="_blank">
 <img src="/assets/imgs/22c0e0d80be77ea4610ed2c865c41b16f9f1262c.jpeg" class="responsive-image" alt="cover" /> 
</a></p>

<style>
  .responsive-image {
    width: 100%;
    height: auto;
  }
</style>]]></content><author><name>張芳睿、薛雅婷</name></author><category term="project" /><category term="開放政府" /><category term="青年參與" /><category term="公私協力" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know what difficulties the protagonist in "Competitive Youth" will encounter in the real world?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1580327344181-c1163234e5a0?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;ixid=MnwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=3867&amp;q=80" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1580327344181-c1163234e5a0?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;ixid=MnwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=3867&amp;q=80" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A Virtuous Circle of Data Altruism</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%95%B8%E6%93%9A%E5%85%AC%E7%9B%8A-%E7%9A%84%E8%89%AF%E5%96%84%E5%BE%AA%E7%92%B0/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Virtuous Circle of Data Altruism" /><published>2022-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E3%80%8C%E6%95%B8%E6%93%9A%E5%85%AC%E7%9B%8A%E3%80%8D%E7%9A%84%E8%89%AF%E5%96%84%E5%BE%AA%E7%92%B0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%95%B8%E6%93%9A%E5%85%AC%E7%9B%8A-%E7%9A%84%E8%89%AF%E5%96%84%E5%BE%AA%E7%92%B0/"><![CDATA[<p>The soulbound tokens (SBTs) concept steamed out of the web3 station to great effect in <a href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/Web3-%E7%9A%84%E9%9D%88%E9%AD%82-SBT-%E6%86%91%E8%AD%89/">my previous column</a>. Many are excited by the prospect of multilateral engagement among individuals and communities. Naturally, an important question surfaced: Is a completely decentralized society with connections through specific mechanisms necessary to achieve co-creation and collaboration?</p>

<p>In fact, collaboration is not limited to a single mechanism. The key lies in openness. Taiwan has opened up many co-creation applications for people-public-private partnerships via open data. Take <a href="https://ci.taiwan.gov.tw/en">Civil IoT Taiwan</a>, for example — it opens sensory data, including air quality, water resources and disaster management built by local agencies using the OGC SensorThings API.</p>

<p>This has produced a steady stream of social creative problem-solving ideas. For example, a smart irrigation system incorporating rainfall warnings and a smart system addressing the needs of clam fisheries are sterling ideas raised by participants in Taiwan’s data application competitions on the basis of the Civil IoT Taiwan.</p>

<p>Based on the data infrastructure, various experiments are proposed by the government and people. Academia Sinica, our national academy, teamed up with community organizations to develop an air box used for monitoring pollution levels. By opening to public participation, air boxes were adopted and distributed across Taiwan. The data is published on the airmap.g0v.tw website, so everyone has another channel to understand air quality in Taiwan without relying solely on the Environmental Protection Administration’s measuring stations.</p>

<p>Another highlight is the “Taiwan Can Help, Health for All” program launched by the government during the pandemic. Utilizing the National Health Insurance Administration’s app, anyone can choose to turn the number of masks they can purchase but did not purchase into humanitarian aid. Namely, they can dedicate masks to those in need around the world. The people can choose to become donors instead of waiting for the data to be released before starting to ponder how best to utilize.</p>

<p>This approach of co-creation for mutual benefit is the origin of the data altruism model our government is proposing this year. The concept is that the data of an individual donor can be processed, or nonpersonal data from an organization can be used, with their consent for public good purposes, and will not endanger the individual or organization.</p>

<p>This is also the essence of the Data Governance Act officially implemented by the European Commission in June. Data altruism emphasizes the beneficial purpose of data for scientific research and improving the public service. Individuals and nonpersonal data holders provide voluntarily free of charge for nonprofit social development. The facilitation of data-sharing benefiting the social environment takes place in an easy and simple way.</p>

<p>Compared with the “open data” model we tend to be more familiar with, the common characteristics of data altruism emphasize the initiative from participants, giving “nonpersonal data” a sense of altruistic purpose. And of course, a digital mutual trust relationship is established accordingly.</p>

<p>In my mind’s eye, data altruism is best seen as an admission ticket. All and sundry can voluntarily and actively provide relevant data as a process of entering an inclusive and welcoming space that brings about real change. When everyone is a producer and a user of data, new co-creation and collaboration relationships are formed in the arrangement and analysis of nonpersonal data. In such a way, true mutual connections are made and a new type of society with digital mutual benefit is developed.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sheau-Tyng Peng</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Social Innovation" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Entering an inclusive and welcoming space that brings about real change.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/92214070_1528843037282109_3836225141944090624_n.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/92214070_1528843037282109_3836225141944090624_n.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Strengthening digital resilience for all</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%BC%B7%E5%8C%96%E5%85%A8%E6%B0%91%E6%95%B8%E4%BD%8D%E9%9F%8C%E6%80%A7/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Strengthening digital resilience for all" /><published>2022-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%BC%B7%E5%8C%96%E5%85%A8%E6%B0%91%E6%95%B8%E4%BD%8D%E9%9F%8C%E6%80%A7</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%BC%B7%E5%8C%96%E5%85%A8%E6%B0%91%E6%95%B8%E4%BD%8D%E9%9F%8C%E6%80%A7/"><![CDATA[<p>Former Estonian President Toomas Hendrik Ilves recently visited Taiwan and attended the Ketagalan Forum. He proposed that democratic countries across Europe, Americas, and Asia, including our country, should form a “Digital Democratic Alliance” that is similar in function to NATO, but not based on geopolitics, but on shared values against authoritarianism.</p>

<p>In fact, specifically regarding this idea, President Ilves <a href="https://www.taiwanplus.com/originals/220708010">generously shared many specific practices and crucial thinking</a> on “how to strengthen digital resilience” back in early July 2022 in the TaiwanPlus program I hosted. Among them, Estonia has already stored important government information abroad for backup and real time synchronization. This is a groundbreaking attempt for the operation of various governments.</p>

<p>This practice originated from the Fukushima incident in 2011. According to President Ilves, after learning that the Japanese government had lost some government information due to the disaster, the Estonian government became wary and thought about how to respond to such situation. In addition to transporting important materials physically to embassies abroad, they also set up servers in embassies. President Ilves pointed out that the Estonian government contacted the Luxembourg government for this purpose, asserting that this server should also be regarded as the territory of Estonia. It cannot be entered without permission and is completely independent. If any important domestic information is changed, it will also be updated to the servers in the embassies simultaneously.</p>

<p>This is not just an innovative approach worthy of reference by governments around the world. The Estonian government has also demonstrated precisely how to build “digital resilience”. What is Resilience? Resilience refers to the ability to quickly recover when affected by adversity at any time, to adapt to changes promptly through perfecting mechanisms, and even to learn from the experiences of being attacked to strengthen one’s own physical fitness. It can be seen that Estonia’s backup mechanism is an important infrastructure for strengthening digital resilience.</p>

<p>In addition, the X-Road architecture jointly operated by the governments of Estonia, Finland and Iceland does not use a single database, but rather provides a “Public Code” as the data exchange layer to avoid excessive concentration of risks and maintain the “heterogeneity” of data, space and usage. This way, even if some portions are attacked, the other nodes remain safe.</p>

<p>And “national cooperation” is also an important inspiration that we get from the Estonian government. As early as 1996, Estonia had provided computers in every school so that students could enter the digital world as early as possible. The government opened up everything from data to code, which not only made digital education universal, but also established digital capabilities of all citizens. In other words, whenever there is an error in the system, anyone has the opportunity to identify and help solve the problem at any time.</p>

<p>Estonia’s experience demonstrates that “plural heterogeneity” and “social resilience” are indispensable. Maintaining diversity in data and systems is the most comprehensive preparation, and having mutual help and protection between the people and the government is the most meticulous security.</p>

<p>“Digital resilience for all citizens” is not only the content of the conversation between President Ilves and I, but also the core concept of the preparatory work of the Ministry of Digital Affairs. From broadband access as human rights to democratic epidemic prevention, Taiwan already has a solid foundation for resilience. Going forward, we will not only create an environment of universal participation for Taiwan, but also continue to create new opportunities for the digital resilience of the Alliance of Democracies.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sheau-Tyng Peng</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Open Government" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Estonia's experience demonstrates that "plural heterogeneity" and "social resilience" are indispensable.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/20220802.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/20220802.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">For a good discussion, there is no need to “talk over the microphone”.</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%A5%BD%E7%9A%84%E8%A8%8E%E8%AB%96-%E6%9C%AA%E5%BF%85%E8%A6%81-%E9%96%8B%E9%BA%A5%E8%AA%AA%E8%A9%B1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="For a good discussion, there is no need to “talk over the microphone”." /><published>2022-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%A5%BD%E7%9A%84%E8%A8%8E%E8%AB%96-%E6%9C%AA%E5%BF%85%E8%A6%81%E3%80%8C%E9%96%8B%E9%BA%A5%E8%AA%AA%E8%A9%B1%E3%80%8D</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%A5%BD%E7%9A%84%E8%A8%8E%E8%AB%96-%E6%9C%AA%E5%BF%85%E8%A6%81-%E9%96%8B%E9%BA%A5%E8%AA%AA%E8%A9%B1/"><![CDATA[<p>Video conferences have become the daily life of modern people; for inclusive discussions, there is no need to open a microphone to speak. Through good guidance and typing-assisted dialogue, discussion participants can express themselves more freely.</p>

<p>The “Let’s Talk” (青年好政) program organized by the Ministry of Education every year, in the face of the epidemic, held an experimental activity with real-time text-assisted discussion, and asked the “Taiwan Labor Front” to invite young people to talk about mental health issues.</p>

<p>In that meeting, there were a lot of flashing avatars in the chat room and the file interface, which didn’t need to be noisy, but also presented a lively atmosphere.</p>

<p>Past deliberations emphasized the presence of people together, and therefore focused on sitting around a table and talking, one after another, voices and expressions. Although this format can make the atmosphere lively, it sometimes crowds out friends who are not good at “speaking out”. Similarly, pressing the microphone icon in a chat room, or being asked to turn on the camera, is also a psychological burden for some people.</p>

<p>Let’s Talk’s “Online Review Demonstration Field” maintains the norms of pre-registration and named participation, but in form, it allows everyone to freely choose whether to “open the microphone” to speak.</p>

<p>Some people feel that voice dialogue requires a two-way sense of feedback, so that they can talk freely; some people feel that they need to type text one after another, so they don’t have to worry about misunderstandings caused by tone and wording.</p>

<p>During the meeting, someone added a sentence before the speech paragraph, “I’m sorry, I type slowly, so I dare to post it after the whole paragraph is finished.” Even if you share the details of multiple personal experiences, it will not occupy the overall meeting. Time, on the contrary, makes everyone more willing to understand each other.</p>

<p>At the same time, many people responded by typing “+1” under the speech paragraphs of other participants, just like the likes and comments on social media. These interactions are not pre-designed discussion guidelines, but spontaneous communication languages in “semi-synchronized” collaborative discussions.</p>

<p>In the past, physical events created appropriate communication by planning food and beverage links and space movements; when turning to online discussions, they could only face the screen individually, and “text” became a buffer, just like a traditional meeting The speech list; the real-time presentation of the co-written document adds to the rhythm of the dialogue.</p>

<p>Most importantly, this “semi-synchronized” discussion method allows participants to “tell the story” at their preferred rhythm. Youth issues are often related to their own experiences. Diverse expression methods not only allow more viewpoints to emerge, but also reduce the impact of oral expression ability, so that different life experiences can be equally reflected in meetings.</p>

<p>Because it was held online, we included not only the voices of young people in northern and southern Taiwan, but also a student from Berlin stayed up all night to participate in the whole process. The student remarked after the meeting: “You can share your personal experience with peace of mind, which is a kind of “de-edge”. I saw empathy in this discussion.”</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, En-en Hsu</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Open Government" /><category term="Youth Participation" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let different life experiences be equally reflected in the meeting.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/woman-gfe6d9bae1_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/woman-gfe6d9bae1_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>