<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-04-26T01:31:30+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/feed.xml</id><author><name>PDIS</name></author><entry><title type="html">Ten years of open data, opening up an infinite future</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%8D%81%E5%B9%B4%E9%96%8B%E6%94%BE%E8%B3%87%E6%96%99-%E9%96%8B%E5%95%9F%E7%84%A1%E9%99%90%E6%9C%AA%E4%BE%86/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ten years of open data, opening up an infinite future" /><published>2023-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%8D%81%E5%B9%B4%E9%96%8B%E6%94%BE%E8%B3%87%E6%96%99-%E9%96%8B%E5%95%9F%E7%84%A1%E9%99%90%E6%9C%AA%E4%BE%86</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%8D%81%E5%B9%B4%E9%96%8B%E6%94%BE%E8%B3%87%E6%96%99-%E9%96%8B%E5%95%9F%E7%84%A1%E9%99%90%E6%9C%AA%E4%BE%86/"><![CDATA[<p>April of this year marks a significant milestone in Taiwan’s development of open data, celebrating the 10th anniversary of the “Government Open Data Platform.” Today, the platform has opened access to more than 55,000 datasets, boasting over 110 million views and 19 million downloads.</p>

<p>Over the years, numerous creative applications that address social issues have emerged from the foundation of open data. For example, innovative ideas, such as an irrigation system that combines rainwater warnings and a smart system designed to help farmers and fishermen cultivate clams, have been proposed by contestants in data application competitions in recent years.</p>

<p>The key to the success of these ideas lies in the continuous release of various types of high impact data by government agencies.</p>

<p>In the past, high impact data with significant public value, such as meteorological observations and disaster relief resources, often faced legal and computational constraints, preventing their easy release. Over the past decade, the government has persevered in overcoming these challenges to provide data for public use.</p>

<p>For instance, the Central Weather Bureau’s “Meteorological Resources Innovation Application Plan,” announced in 2022, opened up access to high-precision meteorological data and resources for legal entities and businesses. This not only improves the accuracy of weather forecasts but also enables the development of targeted meteorological and ocean current analyses for industries like fisheries and shipping.</p>

<p>This case study demonstrates the potential for high-value application data to connect different industries and professions. After soliciting opinions from various ministries and the public, the Digital Ministry has established a “High Application Value Thematic Area” on the Government Open Data Platform.</p>

<p>Departing from the previous classification based on industry or agency, we now categorize data based on “themes” according to social value and content. Initially, six data sets were classified: climate and environment, disaster prevention and rescue, transportation, health and medical care, energy management, and social assistance. Theme-based planning not only aids in data search but also reveals the connections between different data sets, stimulating further collaboration.</p>

<p>For example, the “climate and environment” dataset can contribute to the net-zero transition. The goal of “net-zero” is to minimize human-induced greenhouse gas emissions while offsetting them through negative emissions technologies and forest carbon sinks. In line with the 2021 United Nations Glasgow Climate Agreement, Taiwan proposed a “2050 Net-Zero Emissions Pathway” in March last year and officially implemented the “Climate Change Response Act” this year.</p>

<p>The theme of this year’s Presidential Hackathon International Track, “#FreeTheFuture: Open, Digital &amp; Green,” combines democratic communication, data application, and net-zero carbon emissions, presenting an excellent opportunity for interdisciplinary data sharing and use.</p>

<p>Earth’s natural resources, often depleted due to human over-exploitation, are considered competitive assets, leaving less for future generations. In contrast, open data serves as an “anti-rival good,” where sharing increases its value and contributes to both individuals and the world.</p>

<p>The Digital Ministry will continue to promote the opening and application of data for public good, assisting in the sustainable use of scarce global resources, and welcoming more friends to join our ranks.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sheau-Tyng Peng</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Plural Innovation" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data for public good assists the sustainable use of scarce global resources.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/earth-gab4518d56_1920.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/earth-gab4518d56_1920.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Summit for Democracy: Shaping emerging technologies to align with human rights and democratic principles</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%B0%91%E4%B8%BB%E5%B3%B0%E6%9C%83-%E5%BD%A2%E5%A1%91%E6%96%B0%E8%88%88%E7%A7%91%E6%8A%80%E4%BB%A5%E7%A2%BA%E4%BF%9D%E5%B0%8A%E9%87%8D%E4%BA%BA%E6%AC%8A%E8%88%87%E6%B0%91%E4%B8%BB%E5%8E%9F%E5%89%87/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Summit for Democracy: Shaping emerging technologies to align with human rights and democratic principles" /><published>2023-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%B0%91%E4%B8%BB%E5%B3%B0%E6%9C%83-%E5%BD%A2%E5%A1%91%E6%96%B0%E8%88%88%E7%A7%91%E6%8A%80%E4%BB%A5%E7%A2%BA%E4%BF%9D%E5%B0%8A%E9%87%8D%E4%BA%BA%E6%AC%8A%E8%88%87%E6%B0%91%E4%B8%BB%E5%8E%9F%E5%89%87</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%B0%91%E4%B8%BB%E5%B3%B0%E6%9C%83-%E5%BD%A2%E5%A1%91%E6%96%B0%E8%88%88%E7%A7%91%E6%8A%80%E4%BB%A5%E7%A2%BA%E4%BF%9D%E5%B0%8A%E9%87%8D%E4%BA%BA%E6%AC%8A%E8%88%87%E6%B0%91%E4%B8%BB%E5%8E%9F%E5%89%87/"><![CDATA[<p>Good local time, everyone. I’m Audrey Tang, Taiwan’s digital minister.</p>

<p>It is a genuine honor to participate in the second Summit for Democracy. I will share Taiwan’s experiences in tackling common challenges facing our free and open societies and how emerging technologies strengthen human rights and democratic principles.</p>

<p>Since the inaugural Summit for Democracy in December 2021, the world has fundamentally changed. Russia’s illegal and unprovoked war of aggression against Ukraine has sent shockwaves throughout the international community.</p>

<p>As democracies adapt to this reality, Taiwan shines brightly as a trustworthy and most reliable partner in promoting digital resilience. During the darkest days of COVID-19, our industries rose to the challenge, becoming a potent producer of essential medical supplies. Our civic technology supported the emergence of the Taiwan Can Help model in a global counter-pandemic coalition.</p>

<p>Based on this rock-solid foundation of collaboration, I signed the Declaration for the Future of the Internet in 2022, along with 60 partner countries. The declaration cemented our shared values and
deepened our commitment to democratic allies, paving the way to free the future in the digital realm together.</p>

<p>At the heart of this vision is the Ministry of Digital Affairs (moda), and its objective of “digital resilience for all.” This comprises three levels: Emergency, industrial, and societal resilience.</p>

<p>Emergency resilience impels us to effectively respond to various crises, including cyberattacks and natural disasters. Recent incidents, such as those during the former U.S. House Speaker Nancy Pelosi’s historic visit to Taiwan, unsuccessfully attempted to undermine public trust in our democratic system.</p>

<p>To counter emerging threats, including AI-powered interactive deep fakes, we are consolidating public and private cybersecurity capabilities,
implementing zero-trust principles, and conducting exercises to ensure the seamless operation of critical infrastructure during emergencies.</p>

<p>Starting this year, we’re integrating new satellite providers, enabling multiple networks to reinforce one another across land, sea, and air in times of crisis. The moda website uses IPFS, an emerging technology
for censorship resistance, so everyone can donate connectivity to back us up, while also supporting journalists in autocracies so their reportage remains tamper-free.</p>

<p>Industrial resilience is our commitment to facilitating digital transformation across all sectors while fostering a robust ecosystem. Taiwan possesses a highly advanced IT industry with a world-class semiconductor supply chain and a wealth of experience neutralizing cyberthreats. With global standards such as SEMI E187, we
elevate the Made in Taiwan brand to represent a guarantee of integrity and a solid shield to our democratic partners.</p>

<p>Societal resilience focuses on empowering our civil society by connecting to the democracy network. The moda initiated the Digital News Co-prosperity dialogues with global platforms and brought together the Ministry of Culture, National Communications Commission, and Fair Trade Commission to explore ways of fostering mutually beneficial cooperation with Taiwan’s print, broadcast, and digital journalists.</p>

<p>We believe that accurate news reporting is the bedrock of democracy, and digital competence requires a well-informed and discerning citizenry. In the face of authoritarian expansionism, democracies must confront formidable challenges undermining the delicate equilibrium between societal well-being and individual freedoms. Our efforts must go beyond devising protective measures — we’re envisioning a trajectory embracing the triad of participation, progress, and safety through the power of collective intelligence.</p>

<p>This approach is embodied in the moda’s overarching vision: Plurality, or collaborative diversity. When people from all walks of life can form
digital public spaces together, we can empower the voices reaching across ideological divides and uncover our shared values in plain sight.</p>

<p>As we navigate uncharted waters, I urge you to stand with Taiwan in the pursuit of digital resilience. We must tap into our collective intelligence, innovation, and determination to effect real and lasting change. Let’s embark on this journey and show the world the indomitable spirit of democracy — together.</p>

<p>Thank you. Live long and … prosper.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/e0iHsN0XoWs" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Digital Resilience" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Empower the voices reaching across ideological divides and uncover our shared values in plain sight.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/20230330.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/20230330.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Let drones fly with trust</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E8%AE%93%E7%84%A1%E4%BA%BA%E6%A9%9F%E8%88%87%E4%BF%A1%E4%BB%BB%E9%BD%8A%E9%A3%9B/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Let drones fly with trust" /><published>2023-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E8%AE%93%E7%84%A1%E4%BA%BA%E6%A9%9F%E8%88%87%E4%BF%A1%E4%BB%BB%E9%BD%8A%E9%A3%9B</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E8%AE%93%E7%84%A1%E4%BA%BA%E6%A9%9F%E8%88%87%E4%BF%A1%E4%BB%BB%E9%BD%8A%E9%A3%9B/"><![CDATA[<p>A while ago, my colleagues in the Telecommunications Technology Center (TTC) and I began to discuss the direction of transformation. TTC, under the supervision of the Department of Digital Technology, has made great contributions to the development of telecommunications in the past two decades, from code-carrying services, testing technology to policy think tanks.</p>

<p>In recent years, TTC has fully invested in the development of information security protection and achieved fruitful results. It also makes us think about expanding the “Telecom” in the English name to “Trustworthy Technology Center (Trustworthy Technology Center)”. In line with its core business of helping to strengthen digital resilience.</p>

<p>The “Drone Information Security Joint Test Laboratory” officially established on March 1st, assisted by the National Science Council and jointly built by TTC and industry partners, has set an important record for “Trust Tech” milestone.</p>

<p>UAVs can break through terrain restrictions, and have become an important auxiliary tool from agricultural and forestry surveys to disaster relief. Therefore, the government continues to develop plans for the development of the UAV industry, and combines the energy of industry, government, academia and research to establish the “Taiwan UAV Alliance.”</p>

<p>However, cases of unmanned aerial vehicles being used for attacks and surveillance by some interested people have been heard so far. It has not only become a new information security challenge, but also an important national security issue.</p>

<p>In January of this year, the Joint Test Laboratory, which is still in the preparatory stage, announced the “UAV Security Specifications” based on the opinions of experts and industry representatives from all walks of life. The content covers the three core testing items of the laboratory, including Manufacturer information security maturity, product information security, and site information security.</p>

<p>Taking the first item of manufacturer information security maturity as an example, it is like providing a “security design blueprint” so that the industry can follow clear requirements. The laboratory will check the development process, supply chain, and software and hardware bill of materials management security to ensure the security of the drone development environment and correctly introduce security into product functions.</p>

<p>The second product information security can be regarded as a “health check” for drones. The laboratory is like a health examination center, like providing health examination packages with different safety levels for drones. The higher the number of detection levels that can pass, the more complete the security protection will be. In addition to providing health checks for drones, the laboratory will also analyze problems and produce a complete report for industry reference.</p>

<p>In addition, the third field information security is to strengthen the protection of the UAV activity field to avoid being affected by the environment and other equipment, such as interference during data transmission. Just like in addition to excellent health checkups, we must also pay attention to external risk factors. Only by maintaining a good living environment and diet can we truly ensure our health.</p>

<p>Therefore, the laboratory will also follow the “Guidelines for the Evaluation of Internet of Things Field Information Security Protection” announced by the Taiwan Information and Communications Industry Standards Association, through the processes of threat modeling, vulnerability detection, penetration testing, and impact analysis. Suggestions for improving field information security.</p>

<p>We hope that TTC will not only assist the competent authority, the Ministry of Communications, to jointly establish domestic detection capabilities, but also be in line with international information security standards, and help the industry become a new force in the global drone industry. The Department of Digital Technology and TTC will continue to uphold the spirit of trust in technology to ensure information security that is “easy to defend, hard to attack, tough and reliable”.</p>]]></content><author><name>唐鳳、彭筱婷</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="韌性建設" /><category term="資通安全" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The joint testing laboratory has set an important milestone for "Trust Technology".]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/drone-ttc.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/drone-ttc.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">T-Road and Zero Trust</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/T-Road-%E8%88%87%E9%9B%B6%E4%BF%A1%E4%BB%BB/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="T-Road and Zero Trust" /><published>2023-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/T-Road-%E8%88%87%E9%9B%B6%E4%BF%A1%E4%BB%BB</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/T-Road-%E8%88%87%E9%9B%B6%E4%BF%A1%E4%BB%BB/"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, Taiwan’s first dedicated cybersecurity administrative body, the <a href="https://www.nics.nat.gov.tw/?lang=en">National Institute of Cybersecurity</a> (NICS), was officially established, adding a strong force to the Ministry of Digital Affairs. About the same time, the Ministry of the Interior also revised the <a href="https://www.moi.gov.tw/news_content.aspx?n=145&amp;s=274867">Regulation for Applying for Provision of Household Registration Information and Related Information by Various Agencies.</a>”.</p>

<p>These two events seem unrelated, but in fact, they mark a new chapter in the concept of “cybersecurity equals national security.”</p>

<p>Given that data exchange methods such as CDs and flash drives are easily replicated, lost, or untraceable, the Ministry of the Interior stopped providing household registration data to applying units through these methods since the end of last year. This means that any agency applying to access household registration data can only do so through the government’s Internet Service Network (GSN).</p>

<p>Based on the experience of the Ministry of the Interior, all public agencies that involve national personal information will introduce the “Interagency Data Transmission Exclusive Channel” (T-Road) within the next two years. T-Road transmission is encrypted with agency certificates and is not connected to external service, providing more stringent cybersecurity.</p>

<p>Based on this foundation, our next focus policy is to integrate the “Zero Trust” system with the T-Road network transmission management system and fully introduce it into public agencies with the highest level of cybersecurity.</p>

<p>The traditional cybersecurity framework is based on the distinction between internal and external network permissions, protected by a firewall. The most common approach is that administrators must enter the internal network and input an account password to log into the back end.</p>

<p>However, relying only on the firewall and password for protection is like relying on a single anti-theft door and password lock for an entire building. No matter how stringent the security measures are, if someone intends to steal, they can use the password and pass the security to enter each floor and move freely in each room, causing serious consequences.</p>

<p>The core concept of “Zero Trust” is “Never Trust, Continuously Verify”: anyone, anywhere, at any time, must undergo three verifications of identity, equipment, and behavior patterns when entering any room, even the head of the agency. This way, even if the attacker sneaks into the lobby, they cannot obtain other data because the three verifications at each door are not the same.</p>

<p>From these characteristics, it can be seen that for information systems that require a large amount of transmission and frequent interaction with other units, Zero Trust can prevent malicious actors from stealing data at both ends of the transmission. The complete identity verification trail and undeniable transmission record can more effectively detect insider theft.</p>

<p>T-Road provides a leak-proof secure channel, and “Zero Trust” fills in the gap of a stringent gatekeeping mechanism. Therefore, starting from the Ministry of Digital Affairs’ MyData platform, the T-Road management system will fully introduce the Zero Trust system with three verifications by the end of this year. The Cybersecurity Institute, which broadens the recruitment of cybersecurity professionals and effectively integrates industrial, academic, and research resources, is the project partner to assist various agencies in introducing Zero Trust systems.</p>

<p>In addition to assisting various agencies to strengthen cybersecurity measures, the NICS will also use public code to develop common systems and assist various departments in joint defense against major cybersecurity incidents. Starting from the “Never Trust, Continuously Verify” Zero Trust framework, we aim to create a “Never Stop, Continuously Improve” national digital resilience.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sheau-Tyng Peng</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Digital Service" /><category term="Cyber Security" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Triple verification of identity, equipment, and behavior patterns, even the head of the agency.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/security-2168233_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/security-2168233_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The era of password-free login has arrived</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E4%B8%80%E7%B5%84%E5%B8%B3%E8%99%9F%E8%B5%B0%E9%81%8D%E7%B6%B2%E8%B7%AF%E7%9A%84%E6%99%82%E4%BB%A3%E4%BE%86%E4%BA%86/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The era of password-free login has arrived" /><published>2023-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E4%B8%80%E7%B5%84%E5%B8%B3%E8%99%9F%E8%B5%B0%E9%81%8D%E7%B6%B2%E8%B7%AF%E7%9A%84%E6%99%82%E4%BB%A3%E4%BE%86%E4%BA%86</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E4%B8%80%E7%B5%84%E5%B8%B3%E8%99%9F%E8%B5%B0%E9%81%8D%E7%B6%B2%E8%B7%AF%E7%9A%84%E6%99%82%E4%BB%A3%E4%BE%86%E4%BA%86/"><![CDATA[<p>At the beginning of the new year, we have great news to share with you all: starting this January, the Ministry of Digital Affairs has officially become a member of the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C), an international standard organization. This not only breaks through the past constraint of only being able to join international organizations as a private entity, but it is also a milestone toward the vision of “Plurality”.</p>

<p>At the same time, the Ministry has also joined the FIDO Alliance, which develops and promotes secure and convenient identity standards, becoming the second Taiwanese government unit to become a member after the Ministry of the Interior joined in 2021.</p>

<p>Thanks to the standards set by W3C, websites can be properly displayed on every device, be it a phone, tablet, or computer. In other words, without these standards, even if you have the device, you may not be able to read the website’s content. This means no more seamless streaming, online shopping, or any activity through websites. Its importance to the world is evident.</p>

<p>However, if you want to further interact with other people through the website, such as making videos and publishing articles, you almost always need to register and upload information first. However, account information on a single website often cannot be shared and circulated among different platforms. This not only leads to the monopoly of a few large cross-border platforms, but also limits everyone’s independent right to use data.</p>

<p>Therefore, many communities have developed their own “code portability” solutions, so that everyone can freely choose the most suitable creative environment, fully exercise their data rights, and create more exciting works together. However, there must be a global technical specification to make these solutions truly interoperable with each other.</p>

<p>So in July 2022, W3C launched a brand-new decentralized identity verification standard (DIDs), allowing us to see the dawn of a new generation of digital services. This set of standards allows everyone to directly verify each other’s identities without going through an intermediary service.</p>

<p>We might as well think of this identity mark as an “Internet Passport”. This passport allows everyone to carry their own digital assets; whether it is social posts, photos or videos, it is no longer the cross-border platform that controls these contents, but returns to each creator himself.</p>

<p>If W3C proposes a set of standards for verifying passports, allowing everyone to have their own digital identities; then the FIDO Alliance is responsible for ensuring the security of this passport.</p>

<p>The FIDO Alliance, established in 2013, is an international non-profit organization jointly established by the information industry. Their original intention is to solve the problem of authentication identity. In the past, when logging in to website services, you had to type in your password, which was not only difficult to save, but also faced risks such as account theft and identity fraudulent use.</p>

<p>Therefore, the FIDO Alliance formulated the standard of “password-free login”, and developed various passports for W3C, plus security locks and keys. In this way, everyone can use their passports more safely to roam in the Internet space.</p>

<p>As a member of two major international organizations, the Ministry of Digital Affairs will participate in the formulation of standards according to the needs of all walks of life in Taiwan, and synchronize with the world, and immediately introduce these emerging standards into government agencies, civil society and the industry to practice Plurality – collaborative diversity.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sheau-Tyng Peng</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Democracy Network" /><category term="Digital Industries" /><category term="Cyber Security" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Participate in the formulation of standards and interoperate with the world.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/blockchain-3513216_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/blockchain-3513216_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Send noodle online cloud</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E9%80%81%E9%BA%B5%E7%B7%9A%E4%B8%8A%E9%9B%B2%E7%AB%AF/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Send noodle online cloud" /><published>2022-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E9%80%81%E9%BA%B5%E7%B7%9A%E4%B8%8A%E9%9B%B2%E7%AB%AF</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E9%80%81%E9%BA%B5%E7%B7%9A%E4%B8%8A%E9%9B%B2%E7%AB%AF/"><![CDATA[<p>A few days ago, my colleagues from the Industrial Development Administration and I went to the oil depot in Banqiao to learn about the application of the <a href="https://www.tcloud.gov.tw/">Taiwan Cloud Market</a> platform . The store has been in business for 36 years. From roadside stalls to storefronts, it is already a time-honored snack bar in Banqiao. The steaming noodles and the sweet and plump oysters are impressive.</p>

<p>The boss said that they usually start preparing materials at six o’clock in the morning, and then open the store from nine thirty in the morning until seven o’clock in the evening. Even if there is an endless stream of customers, the well-trained clerks keep the queue from stagnating. From ordering to checkout, the meal can be served in an average of five minutes.</p>

<p>However, at the same time, the clerks are still overwhelmed with various customized needs such as on-site ordering and delivery, answering reservation calls, confirming takeaway orders, and “no coriander”. Recording and verbal transmission using only pen and paper is time-consuming and error-prone.</p>

<p>This problem has found an effective solution through the “Taiwan Cloud Market” platform promoted by the Digital Industry Agency of the Ministry of Digital Affairs.</p>

<p>“Taiwan Cloud Bazaar” integrates cross-agency processes such as the Ministry of Finance, the Ministry of the Interior, and the Ministry of Economic Affairs, and selects various cloud tools and services suitable for small and medium-sized enterprises into a single platform.</p>

<p>As long as it meets the certification standards of small and medium-sized enterprises, or is a profit-making enterprise with tax registration, in just ten minutes, all procedures such as application, review and signing can be completed on the cloud market website, and the digital transformation plan can be directly purchased. You can also get up to 30,000 yuan in digital point subsidies. If you don’t know how to choose the right solution, there are also expert consultants online to provide assistance.</p>

<p>Through the cloud market, Youkukou Noodle Shop adopts the “Quicker Line Ordering Customer Service System” to provide customers with 24-hour online ordering and online payment.</p>

<p>Through digital operation, the clerk no longer needs to answer the phone, and the verbal confirmation time of about three minutes is eliminated for each order. Moreover, because of the online ordering system, it has reached a wider customer base and increased the consumption of online group buying, and the average unit price of each customer has increased by at least two times. In addition, through data collection, it is also helpful for raw material management, making the purchase cost more accurate.</p>

<p>From the story of Youkukou noodle shop, we can see that the cloud service with open subscription system and transferable data is an important digital transformation tool for SME partners. Therefore, in addition to helping more business partners introduce cloud solutions through the cloud market, we also encourage service providers to continue to innovate through the “Digital Cloud Service Thematic R&amp;D Subsidy Program” and develop simple and easy-to-use cloud solutions for all walks of life. plan.</p>

<p>At present, “Taiwan Cloud Market” has collected 15 types of cloud solutions such as online store opening, marketing promotion, remote office, enterprise management, customer service, and market analysis. As of November this year, there have been more than 15 cloud solutions Thirty-six thousand companies use it.</p>

<p>All walks of life have different operating objectives. The Digital Department continues to assist everyone in finding suitable digital tools and cloud services, so that all kinds of carefully crafted services and products can be delivered to customers easily and simply.</p>]]></content><author><name>唐鳳、彭筱婷</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="數位產業" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA["Taiwan Cloud Marketplace" has been used by more than 36,000 companies.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/digitization-7580781_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/digitization-7580781_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Made in Taiwan Reliable and Reliable</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E8%87%BA%E7%81%A3%E8%A3%BD%E9%80%A0-%E4%BF%A1%E8%B3%B4%E5%8F%AF%E9%9D%A0/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Made in Taiwan Reliable and Reliable" /><published>2022-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E8%87%BA%E7%81%A3%E8%A3%BD%E9%80%A0-%E4%BF%A1%E8%B3%B4%E5%8F%AF%E9%9D%A0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E8%87%BA%E7%81%A3%E8%A3%BD%E9%80%A0-%E4%BF%A1%E8%B3%B4%E5%8F%AF%E9%9D%A0/"><![CDATA[<p>A while ago, FCC Commissioner Brendan Carr visited Taiwan for the first time. When visiting the Ministry of Digital Technology, he pointed out that Taiwan is a reliable economic and national security partner, and he very much looks forward to the deepening of cooperation between the two sides in matters related to information security.</p>

<p>Commissioner Karl’s statement has its own reasons. Taiwan has become the world leader in semiconductor and information and communication manufacturing, and has the most complete industrial supply chain in the world. And we are at the forefront of overseas cyber attacks, and we have rich practical experience in information security.</p>

<p>With the recent rapid changes in the international situation, governments of various countries are paying more and more attention to the security risks of technology products. For example, the United Kingdom announced that it will completely remove Huawei’s 5G products by 2027. Therefore, the digital department will integrate “industrial information security” and “information security industry” to create a reliable supply chain.</p>

<p>In terms of strengthening industrial information security, in January this year, the world’s first semiconductor information security standard “SEMI E187” jointly created by Taiwan’s industry, government, academia and research circles was officially released. Is the device secure. In order to help more operators to use it, practical operation guidelines were also released in October to guide the industry in evaluating whether the product complies with the regulations.</p>

<p>In addition, in the past, Chinese manufacturers could only send chips to foreign laboratories for safety testing. If the inspection failed, the industry had to modify the product before sending it for inspection, resulting in high costs.</p>

<p>Now, the “Chip Security Joint Testing Laboratory” is jointly established by the Ministry of Digital Industry, the academic community and the industry, providing local testing for the industry to enter the international market at a lower cost and faster.</p>

<p>From these experiences, it can be seen that information security is already a necessary investment in semiconductors and even all walks of life; Taiwan began to promote the “six core strategic industries” two years ago, including the excellent information security industry.</p>

<p>In recent years, Taiwan’s new information security enterprises have also made significant progress in “quality” and “quantity”. Up to now, 28 information security innovations have been established, among which Laiyi Digital and Boou Technology have also won the In the past two years, he has won the first prize in the field of network security of SelectUSA, an investment summit in the United States.</p>

<p>As a digital “coach” for various industries, the Ministry of Digital Industry has also built Taiwan’s first information security practice base “Shalun Information Security Service Base” to help strengthen industrial information security and promote the information security industry.</p>

<p>The information security base simulated and designed twelve sets of attack scenarios based on information security incidents at home and abroad. In response to these scenarios, we have also cooperated with domestic information security companies to develop defensive countermeasures. The team can not only use it to participate in the actual test, grasp the advantages and disadvantages of their own products, but also learn more about suitable solutions.</p>

<p>In other words, the information security service base is not only a training ground for information security manufacturers, but also a platform for matching supply and demand and gathering business opportunities in the information security industry.</p>

<p>Made in Taiwan (MIT) has always been a quality assurance. Today, T not only represents Taiwan, but also means trustworthiness. By strengthening industrial information security and developing the information security industry, the Digital Division will let the world see: “Made in Taiwan means trust and reliability.”</p>]]></content><author><name>唐鳳、彭筱婷</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="數位產業" /><category term="資通安全" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[MIT has always been a guarantee of quality. Today, T is more trustworthy (Trustworthiness).]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/hands-1947915_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/hands-1947915_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Idea loose, build infinite future</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E9%BB%9E%E5%AD%90%E6%9D%BE-%E6%89%93%E9%80%A0%E7%84%A1%E9%99%90%E6%9C%AA%E4%BE%86/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Idea loose, build infinite future" /><published>2022-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E9%BB%9E%E5%AD%90%E6%9D%BE%EF%BC%8C%E6%89%93%E9%80%A0%E7%84%A1%E9%99%90%E6%9C%AA%E4%BE%86</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E9%BB%9E%E5%AD%90%E6%9D%BE-%E6%89%93%E9%80%A0%E7%84%A1%E9%99%90%E6%9C%AA%E4%BE%86/"><![CDATA[<p>The hashtag for the Ministry of Digital Development, why #FreeTheFuture?</p>

<p>Decades ago, the well-known science fiction writer William Gibson (William Gibson) experienced the emerging virtual reality (VR) technology and expressed his feelings: “The future has come, but it is not evenly distributed.” At that time VR is not yet mature enough to be a part of everyday life, but the experience has given him a glimpse into the future.</p>

<p>Free the Future means that the future has infinite possibilities, because the digital world can not only break the limitation of time and space, but also allow us to communicate and co-create with all kinds of people, so that imaginary things can become reality.</p>

<p>In the past few years, Taiwan has achieved many fruitful results of national cooperation. For example, for friends at home and abroad who are interested in improving government digital services, the “Presidents Cup Hackathon” provides a place to realize good ideas, and has now become a milestone in Taiwan’s public innovation.</p>

<p>The Digital Development Department has been planning since the preparatory period. Through co-creation by the whole people, the physical interpersonal network will be further expanded into a multiverse of “co-presence, code-carrying interoperability”. “Idea Pine” hopes to take a step towards the future through the unlimited imagination of the whole people.</p>

<p>In view of the fact that 6G technology will mature around 2040, related applications will shape the future life. The future is originally formed by everyone’s imagination,</p>

<p>Therefore, this year’s first Ideas Song takes “WeWe Futures: 2040 Multiverse (Plurality)” as the theme, open to individual and group submissions, and also provides virtual and real The inclusive and immersive performance allows all people to discuss our expectations for 2040 through personal participation.</p>

<p>How is IdeaThon different from other hackathons? In the past, the Presidents Cup Hackathon was open to citizens to make wishes, and several experts proposed solutions and implemented them on the ground; Ideasong welcomed social co-creation and invited all citizens to explore the possibility of the future together.</p>

<p>In other words, Ideasong is completely open to all kinds of submission forms. On the basis of hackathons, it breaks away from the achievements of website applications in the past, and further expands the thinking and actions of the participation of the whole people.</p>

<p>“Future News” individual competition, all individuals are welcome to create events or reports that may happen in 2040, not limited to video, text or multimedia; “Future Prototype” team competition encourages the development of design concepts for 2040, including tangible Space commodities, intangible service mechanisms, or living entities. As long as you are shortlisted, you will receive interdisciplinary expert guidance, and through the assistance of extended reality technology, you will produce a prototype of the concept.</p>

<p>In 2015, after experiencing VR again, Gibson said: “They did it!” The novelist who had already described the digital world before the Internet was popular, saw the future he described actually come.</p>

<p>No one can accurately predict the future, but everyone can bring the outline of the future to the present through imagination and creation, and then realize it through co-creation. This is the original intention of Ideasong, and also the expectation of the Digital Department: co-creation by all people, so that the future comes through everyone.</p>]]></content><author><name>唐鳳、彭筱婷</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="數位策略" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Co-creation by the whole people, let the future come through everyone.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/light-bulbs-1407610_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/light-bulbs-1407610_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What is a multiverse?</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E4%BB%80%E9%BA%BC%E6%98%AF%E5%A4%9A%E5%85%83%E5%AE%87%E5%AE%99/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is a multiverse?" /><published>2022-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E4%BB%80%E9%BA%BC%E6%98%AF%E5%A4%9A%E5%85%83%E5%AE%87%E5%AE%99</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E4%BB%80%E9%BA%BC%E6%98%AF%E5%A4%9A%E5%85%83%E5%AE%87%E5%AE%99/"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, many friends are very curious about the “Multiverse Division” of the Digital Development Department. Is it like the plots that have appeared in science fiction works, where there are multiple completely different societies on different timelines? And is the multiverse science going to “govern” these different societies?</p>

<p>This is indeed quite creative thinking. However, just as the Digital Development Department does not conduct supervision business, the Multiverse Division is not the “Time Variation Administration” in the comics. The existence of this section is to allow the “metaverse” (metaverse) to communicate with each other and create new applications freely.</p>

<p>The currently known Metaverse is extended through AR (augmented reality), VR (virtual reality) and other digital technologies, allowing people to appear as their own avatars in a world constructed in a virtual environment. However, the current virtual world can only interact within a specific digital platform, which virtually limits the possibility of innovation.</p>

<p>How to break the restriction and communicate directly? In fact, in our lives, the practice of multiverses has been practically applied everywhere.</p>

<p>Mobile phone number is a good example. Not only can you call across telecommunication providers, but you can also “carry codes” at any time to transfer your original mobile phone number to the telecommunication provider you want to use. The advantage of this is that everyone has more choices. You don’t need to re-register your phone number and rebuild all your contact information, and you can freely choose your preferred service.</p>

<p>However, the current large-scale cross-border digital platforms are not like this, and accounts are limited to use within the platform. Just like a mobile phone, it only has the function of calling within the network, and cannot call the numbers of other telecom operators. If you want to connect with others through different platforms, you must create an account on each platform. It’s like everyone has to print several business cards, and the information on each business card cannot be updated synchronously.</p>

<p>Such restrictions virtually stifle the possibility of innovation. Because all accounts must be approved by the platform, they can only be shared on a single platform. Moreover, the platform side controls all interactive data under each account, which poses risks to privacy and information security.</p>

<p>If you want to freely connect and interact with other people without being influenced by the middle platform, you can use the “end-to-end encryption” method. That is, only the endpoints actually participating can see each other’s messages, and the interaction will not be intercepted and recorded. This is the core concept of the “multiverse”: everyone can freely choose different channels to connect to each other securely.</p>

<p>What can multiverse science do? In fact, there are precedents to follow. More than ten years ago, instant messages in the Internet world could communicate with each other across platforms. E-mail is one of the earliest interoperable applications, and everyone can freely send to mailboxes in other domains.</p>

<p>Use appropriate tools to communicate with each other, and then build consensus and spread innovation. This is the vision of the “Future Internet Manifesto”, which is the “multiverse” that Taiwan is developing.</p>

<p>Through a point-to-point, multi-center, and decentralized architecture, the Digital Development Department will continue to use the concept of interoperability to promote innovative applications that reflect local needs, creating an infinite future for Taiwan and the world.</p>]]></content><author><name>唐鳳、彭筱婷</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="民主網絡" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everyone can freely choose different channels to connect with each other securely.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/team-4200837_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/team-4200837_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Moda begins with Public Code</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%95%B8%E4%BD%8D%E9%83%A8%E5%BE%9E%E5%B0%8E%E5%85%A5%E5%85%AC%E5%85%B1%E7%A8%8B%E5%BC%8F%E9%96%8B%E5%A7%8B/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Moda begins with Public Code" /><published>2022-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%95%B8%E4%BD%8D%E9%83%A8%E5%BE%9E%E5%B0%8E%E5%85%A5%E5%85%AC%E5%85%B1%E7%A8%8B%E5%BC%8F%E9%96%8B%E5%A7%8B</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%95%B8%E4%BD%8D%E9%83%A8%E5%BE%9E%E5%B0%8E%E5%85%A5%E5%85%AC%E5%85%B1%E7%A8%8B%E5%BC%8F%E9%96%8B%E5%A7%8B/"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, Taiwan has faced a lot of foreign interference. On August 2 alone, the websites of government agencies were attacked by hackers. In terms of distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) traffic, it was 23 times higher than the previous record of traffic volume in a single day.</p>

<p>Under such high-density pressure, it is fortunate that the information security personnel of various agencies can adjust the structure and respond quickly. This also confirms the importance of “digital resilience”.</p>

<p>Next, we will continue to strengthen our physical fitness. Regarding the results of the implementation of open licensing in recent years, the Ministry of Digital Development will use the “public code” as the core to further strengthen digital resilience.</p>

<p>Why is the key to public programs? In the past, free software, which was freely used and collaborative, started the “open source” movement and encouraged developers to publish code.</p>

<p>But only government agencies, due to organizational and regulatory constraints, make it difficult to import free software; the system of each unit often hinders interoperability due to different specifications. If there is a problem, it is difficult for other departments to immediately support.</p>

<p>In order to completely reverse the deadlock and expand social and economic development with a digital base, the European Free Software Foundation (FSFE) has initiated the “public money, public code” movement since 2017, advocating “ The system programs established by the government should be fully disclosed, with clear guidelines and specifications.”</p>

<p>For example, to improve the digital resilience of the official website of the government, we can make good use of public programs, deploy a decentralized structure, and create a “plurality” of services. Even if a certain part is attacked, the security and availability of the system can still be maintained through the joint defense mechanism.</p>

<p>The most important transnational case in recent years, X-Road, is a system jointly maintained by the governments of Estonia, Finland and Iceland. Governments of all countries can use it freely in their own countries, such as applying for subsidies, renewing driver’s licenses, etc. Once problems are found, they can immediately make corrections and feed them back to the system, so that other units can update them synchronously.</p>

<p>As can be seen from X-Road, public programs are like transnational railways. Countries share the same tracks, schedules, and even carriage specifications, while railway tracks and related facilities in different countries are maintained and operated by that country. If one of the countries fixes track problems or develops new parts, it will also inform other countries to share experience and improve quality.</p>

<p>X-Road has created a milestone in the government’s digital practice, showing us that public programs are not only a protective net for information security, but also have the opportunity to create a democratic ecology of symbiosis, sharing and co-creation.</p>

<p>For this reason, I also proposed to join CC0 (public domain contribution, refers to free software that is not restricted by copyright), and join the international <a href="https://standard.publiccode.net/">Public Code Standard</a>. In this way, as long as the materials and content authorized by CC0 are used, they have the opportunity to enter the digital infrastructure of governments at all levels.</p>

<p>In the preparatory stage, the Digital Development Department has been exploring with the service providers how to introduce the concept of public programs. In the future, our content and programs will gradually adopt CC0 authorization and release them to the public domain, so as to share the foundation of resilience with democratic partners and create a model of digital governance.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sheau-Tyng Peng</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Open Government" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As you can see from X-Road, public code are like cross-country railways.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/rails-gb4c806ad8_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/rails-gb4c806ad8_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>