<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-02-08T04:51:21+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/feed.xml</id><author><name>PDIS</name></author><entry><title type="html">Moda begins with Public Code</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%95%B8%E4%BD%8D%E9%83%A8%E5%BE%9E%E5%B0%8E%E5%85%A5%E5%85%AC%E5%85%B1%E7%A8%8B%E5%BC%8F%E9%96%8B%E5%A7%8B/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Moda begins with Public Code" /><published>2022-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%95%B8%E4%BD%8D%E9%83%A8%E5%BE%9E%E5%B0%8E%E5%85%A5%E5%85%AC%E5%85%B1%E7%A8%8B%E5%BC%8F%E9%96%8B%E5%A7%8B</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%95%B8%E4%BD%8D%E9%83%A8%E5%BE%9E%E5%B0%8E%E5%85%A5%E5%85%AC%E5%85%B1%E7%A8%8B%E5%BC%8F%E9%96%8B%E5%A7%8B/"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, Taiwan has faced a lot of foreign interference. On August 2 alone, the websites of government agencies were attacked by hackers. In terms of distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) traffic, it was 23 times higher than the previous record of traffic volume in a single day.</p>

<p>Under such high-density pressure, it is fortunate that the information security personnel of various agencies can adjust the structure and respond quickly. This also confirms the importance of “digital resilience”.</p>

<p>Next, we will continue to strengthen our physical fitness. Regarding the results of the implementation of open licensing in recent years, the Ministry of Digital Development will use the “public code” as the core to further strengthen digital resilience.</p>

<p>Why is the key to public programs? In the past, free software, which was freely used and collaborative, started the “open source” movement and encouraged developers to publish code.</p>

<p>But only government agencies, due to organizational and regulatory constraints, make it difficult to import free software; the system of each unit often hinders interoperability due to different specifications. If there is a problem, it is difficult for other departments to immediately support.</p>

<p>In order to completely reverse the deadlock and expand social and economic development with a digital base, the European Free Software Foundation (FSFE) has initiated the “public money, public code” movement since 2017, advocating “ The system programs established by the government should be fully disclosed, with clear guidelines and specifications.”</p>

<p>For example, to improve the digital resilience of the official website of the government, we can make good use of public programs, deploy a decentralized structure, and create a “plurality” of services. Even if a certain part is attacked, the security and availability of the system can still be maintained through the joint defense mechanism.</p>

<p>The most important transnational case in recent years, X-Road, is a system jointly maintained by the governments of Estonia, Finland and Iceland. Governments of all countries can use it freely in their own countries, such as applying for subsidies, renewing driver’s licenses, etc. Once problems are found, they can immediately make corrections and feed them back to the system, so that other units can update them synchronously.</p>

<p>As can be seen from X-Road, public programs are like transnational railways. Countries share the same tracks, schedules, and even carriage specifications, while railway tracks and related facilities in different countries are maintained and operated by that country. If one of the countries fixes track problems or develops new parts, it will also inform other countries to share experience and improve quality.</p>

<p>X-Road has created a milestone in the government’s digital practice, showing us that public programs are not only a protective net for information security, but also have the opportunity to create a democratic ecology of symbiosis, sharing and co-creation.</p>

<p>For this reason, I also proposed to join CC0 (public domain contribution, refers to free software that is not restricted by copyright), and join the international <a href="https://standard.publiccode.net/">Public Code Standard</a>. In this way, as long as the materials and content authorized by CC0 are used, they have the opportunity to enter the digital infrastructure of governments at all levels.</p>

<p>In the preparatory stage, the Digital Development Department has been exploring with the service providers how to introduce the concept of public programs. In the future, our content and programs will gradually adopt CC0 authorization and release them to the public domain, so as to share the foundation of resilience with democratic partners and create a model of digital governance.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sheau-Tyng Peng</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Open Government" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As you can see from X-Road, public code are like cross-country railways.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/rails-gb4c806ad8_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/rails-gb4c806ad8_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Esports Policy Resume</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/project/esports/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Esports Policy Resume" /><published>2022-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/project/esports</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/project/esports/"><![CDATA[<p>The game market research agency NEWZOO released a special article on the “2021 Global E-sports and Live Streaming Market Report” in March 2021. According to the report, the global e-sports market revenue will increase from $947.1 million last year to $1.084 billion, With an annual growth rate of 14.5%, it can be seen that the e-sports industry will be an emerging industry just around the corner.</p>

<p>However, before 2017, in order to develop the prospects of e-sports talents in the e-sports business, and to carry out Taiwan e-sports-related matters, including professional courses, alternative service for players, and related regulations, a series of inter-departmental meetings were held. There will be a business rights and responsibility coordination meeting on how to create a suitable environment for e-sports talents.</p>

<p>In the process, we adhered to the "innovative" meeting method within the "Open Government" of the Office, and applied and opened up the four core principles of the government - "transparency", "participation", "responsibility", and "containment". At the very beginning, take stock of the viewpoints of stakeholders (e-sports players, NGOs, government ministries, members of the Legislative Yuan, schools, etc.), and ensure that every discussion has a record. This is the first demonstration of transparency. Verbatim and public, became the main niche of open government.</p>

<p>Next, let the verbatim draft of the discussion process in the open meeting, through the process of formal policy discussion, through digital dialogue, bring the feasible and constructive opinions of netizens on the Internet back to the reference during the discussion process , which not only sets the best example for the new discussion methods of "participation", "responsibility", and "accommodation", but also effectively tracks the unresolved issues before, making the progress of each time open online, which really brings the mutual trust between the government and the people closer. Set up a more stable pace of discussion in the future.</p>

<p><a href="https://pdis-tw.kumu.io/電子競技政策履歷?token=dG0IhKBVoh7dj0BB" target="_blank">Policy History</a></p>

<p><a href="https://pdis-tw.kumu.io/電子競技政策履歷?token=dG0IhKBVoh7dj0BB" target="_blank">
 <img src="/assets/imgs/22c0e0d80be77ea4610ed2c865c41b16f9f1262c.jpeg" class="responsive-image" alt="cover" /> 
</a></p>

<style>
  .responsive-image {
    width: 100%;
    height: auto;
  }
</style>]]></content><author><name>張芳睿、薛雅婷</name></author><category term="project" /><category term="開放政府" /><category term="青年參與" /><category term="公私協力" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know what difficulties the protagonist in "Competitive Youth" will encounter in the real world?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1580327344181-c1163234e5a0?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;ixid=MnwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=3867&amp;q=80" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1580327344181-c1163234e5a0?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;ixid=MnwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=3867&amp;q=80" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A Virtuous Circle of Data Altruism</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%95%B8%E6%93%9A%E5%85%AC%E7%9B%8A-%E7%9A%84%E8%89%AF%E5%96%84%E5%BE%AA%E7%92%B0/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Virtuous Circle of Data Altruism" /><published>2022-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E3%80%8C%E6%95%B8%E6%93%9A%E5%85%AC%E7%9B%8A%E3%80%8D%E7%9A%84%E8%89%AF%E5%96%84%E5%BE%AA%E7%92%B0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%95%B8%E6%93%9A%E5%85%AC%E7%9B%8A-%E7%9A%84%E8%89%AF%E5%96%84%E5%BE%AA%E7%92%B0/"><![CDATA[<p>The soulbound tokens (SBTs) concept steamed out of the web3 station to great effect in <a href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/Web3-%E7%9A%84%E9%9D%88%E9%AD%82-SBT-%E6%86%91%E8%AD%89/">my previous column</a>. Many are excited by the prospect of multilateral engagement among individuals and communities. Naturally, an important question surfaced: Is a completely decentralized society with connections through specific mechanisms necessary to achieve co-creation and collaboration?</p>

<p>In fact, collaboration is not limited to a single mechanism. The key lies in openness. Taiwan has opened up many co-creation applications for people-public-private partnerships via open data. Take <a href="https://ci.taiwan.gov.tw/en">Civil IoT Taiwan</a>, for example — it opens sensory data, including air quality, water resources and disaster management built by local agencies using the OGC SensorThings API.</p>

<p>This has produced a steady stream of social creative problem-solving ideas. For example, a smart irrigation system incorporating rainfall warnings and a smart system addressing the needs of clam fisheries are sterling ideas raised by participants in Taiwan’s data application competitions on the basis of the Civil IoT Taiwan.</p>

<p>Based on the data infrastructure, various experiments are proposed by the government and people. Academia Sinica, our national academy, teamed up with community organizations to develop an air box used for monitoring pollution levels. By opening to public participation, air boxes were adopted and distributed across Taiwan. The data is published on the airmap.g0v.tw website, so everyone has another channel to understand air quality in Taiwan without relying solely on the Environmental Protection Administration’s measuring stations.</p>

<p>Another highlight is the “Taiwan Can Help, Health for All” program launched by the government during the pandemic. Utilizing the National Health Insurance Administration’s app, anyone can choose to turn the number of masks they can purchase but did not purchase into humanitarian aid. Namely, they can dedicate masks to those in need around the world. The people can choose to become donors instead of waiting for the data to be released before starting to ponder how best to utilize.</p>

<p>This approach of co-creation for mutual benefit is the origin of the data altruism model our government is proposing this year. The concept is that the data of an individual donor can be processed, or nonpersonal data from an organization can be used, with their consent for public good purposes, and will not endanger the individual or organization.</p>

<p>This is also the essence of the Data Governance Act officially implemented by the European Commission in June. Data altruism emphasizes the beneficial purpose of data for scientific research and improving the public service. Individuals and nonpersonal data holders provide voluntarily free of charge for nonprofit social development. The facilitation of data-sharing benefiting the social environment takes place in an easy and simple way.</p>

<p>Compared with the “open data” model we tend to be more familiar with, the common characteristics of data altruism emphasize the initiative from participants, giving “nonpersonal data” a sense of altruistic purpose. And of course, a digital mutual trust relationship is established accordingly.</p>

<p>In my mind’s eye, data altruism is best seen as an admission ticket. All and sundry can voluntarily and actively provide relevant data as a process of entering an inclusive and welcoming space that brings about real change. When everyone is a producer and a user of data, new co-creation and collaboration relationships are formed in the arrangement and analysis of nonpersonal data. In such a way, true mutual connections are made and a new type of society with digital mutual benefit is developed.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sheau-Tyng Peng</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Social Innovation" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Entering an inclusive and welcoming space that brings about real change.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/92214070_1528843037282109_3836225141944090624_n.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/92214070_1528843037282109_3836225141944090624_n.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Strengthening digital resilience for all</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%BC%B7%E5%8C%96%E5%85%A8%E6%B0%91%E6%95%B8%E4%BD%8D%E9%9F%8C%E6%80%A7/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Strengthening digital resilience for all" /><published>2022-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%BC%B7%E5%8C%96%E5%85%A8%E6%B0%91%E6%95%B8%E4%BD%8D%E9%9F%8C%E6%80%A7</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%BC%B7%E5%8C%96%E5%85%A8%E6%B0%91%E6%95%B8%E4%BD%8D%E9%9F%8C%E6%80%A7/"><![CDATA[<p>Former Estonian President Toomas Hendrik Ilves recently visited Taiwan and attended the Ketagalan Forum. He proposed that democratic countries across Europe, Americas, and Asia, including our country, should form a “Digital Democratic Alliance” that is similar in function to NATO, but not based on geopolitics, but on shared values against authoritarianism.</p>

<p>In fact, specifically regarding this idea, President Ilves <a href="https://www.taiwanplus.com/originals/220708010">generously shared many specific practices and crucial thinking</a> on “how to strengthen digital resilience” back in early July 2022 in the TaiwanPlus program I hosted. Among them, Estonia has already stored important government information abroad for backup and real time synchronization. This is a groundbreaking attempt for the operation of various governments.</p>

<p>This practice originated from the Fukushima incident in 2011. According to President Ilves, after learning that the Japanese government had lost some government information due to the disaster, the Estonian government became wary and thought about how to respond to such situation. In addition to transporting important materials physically to embassies abroad, they also set up servers in embassies. President Ilves pointed out that the Estonian government contacted the Luxembourg government for this purpose, asserting that this server should also be regarded as the territory of Estonia. It cannot be entered without permission and is completely independent. If any important domestic information is changed, it will also be updated to the servers in the embassies simultaneously.</p>

<p>This is not just an innovative approach worthy of reference by governments around the world. The Estonian government has also demonstrated precisely how to build “digital resilience”. What is Resilience? Resilience refers to the ability to quickly recover when affected by adversity at any time, to adapt to changes promptly through perfecting mechanisms, and even to learn from the experiences of being attacked to strengthen one’s own physical fitness. It can be seen that Estonia’s backup mechanism is an important infrastructure for strengthening digital resilience.</p>

<p>In addition, the X-Road architecture jointly operated by the governments of Estonia, Finland and Iceland does not use a single database, but rather provides a “Public Code” as the data exchange layer to avoid excessive concentration of risks and maintain the “heterogeneity” of data, space and usage. This way, even if some portions are attacked, the other nodes remain safe.</p>

<p>And “national cooperation” is also an important inspiration that we get from the Estonian government. As early as 1996, Estonia had provided computers in every school so that students could enter the digital world as early as possible. The government opened up everything from data to code, which not only made digital education universal, but also established digital capabilities of all citizens. In other words, whenever there is an error in the system, anyone has the opportunity to identify and help solve the problem at any time.</p>

<p>Estonia’s experience demonstrates that “plural heterogeneity” and “social resilience” are indispensable. Maintaining diversity in data and systems is the most comprehensive preparation, and having mutual help and protection between the people and the government is the most meticulous security.</p>

<p>“Digital resilience for all citizens” is not only the content of the conversation between President Ilves and I, but also the core concept of the preparatory work of the Ministry of Digital Affairs. From broadband access as human rights to democratic epidemic prevention, Taiwan already has a solid foundation for resilience. Going forward, we will not only create an environment of universal participation for Taiwan, but also continue to create new opportunities for the digital resilience of the Alliance of Democracies.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sheau-Tyng Peng</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Open Government" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Estonia's experience demonstrates that "plural heterogeneity" and "social resilience" are indispensable.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/20220802.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/20220802.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">For a good discussion, there is no need to “talk over the microphone”.</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%A5%BD%E7%9A%84%E8%A8%8E%E8%AB%96-%E6%9C%AA%E5%BF%85%E8%A6%81-%E9%96%8B%E9%BA%A5%E8%AA%AA%E8%A9%B1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="For a good discussion, there is no need to “talk over the microphone”." /><published>2022-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%A5%BD%E7%9A%84%E8%A8%8E%E8%AB%96-%E6%9C%AA%E5%BF%85%E8%A6%81%E3%80%8C%E9%96%8B%E9%BA%A5%E8%AA%AA%E8%A9%B1%E3%80%8D</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%A5%BD%E7%9A%84%E8%A8%8E%E8%AB%96-%E6%9C%AA%E5%BF%85%E8%A6%81-%E9%96%8B%E9%BA%A5%E8%AA%AA%E8%A9%B1/"><![CDATA[<p>Video conferences have become the daily life of modern people; for inclusive discussions, there is no need to open a microphone to speak. Through good guidance and typing-assisted dialogue, discussion participants can express themselves more freely.</p>

<p>The “Let’s Talk” (青年好政) program organized by the Ministry of Education every year, in the face of the epidemic, held an experimental activity with real-time text-assisted discussion, and asked the “Taiwan Labor Front” to invite young people to talk about mental health issues.</p>

<p>In that meeting, there were a lot of flashing avatars in the chat room and the file interface, which didn’t need to be noisy, but also presented a lively atmosphere.</p>

<p>Past deliberations emphasized the presence of people together, and therefore focused on sitting around a table and talking, one after another, voices and expressions. Although this format can make the atmosphere lively, it sometimes crowds out friends who are not good at “speaking out”. Similarly, pressing the microphone icon in a chat room, or being asked to turn on the camera, is also a psychological burden for some people.</p>

<p>Let’s Talk’s “Online Review Demonstration Field” maintains the norms of pre-registration and named participation, but in form, it allows everyone to freely choose whether to “open the microphone” to speak.</p>

<p>Some people feel that voice dialogue requires a two-way sense of feedback, so that they can talk freely; some people feel that they need to type text one after another, so they don’t have to worry about misunderstandings caused by tone and wording.</p>

<p>During the meeting, someone added a sentence before the speech paragraph, “I’m sorry, I type slowly, so I dare to post it after the whole paragraph is finished.” Even if you share the details of multiple personal experiences, it will not occupy the overall meeting. Time, on the contrary, makes everyone more willing to understand each other.</p>

<p>At the same time, many people responded by typing “+1” under the speech paragraphs of other participants, just like the likes and comments on social media. These interactions are not pre-designed discussion guidelines, but spontaneous communication languages in “semi-synchronized” collaborative discussions.</p>

<p>In the past, physical events created appropriate communication by planning food and beverage links and space movements; when turning to online discussions, they could only face the screen individually, and “text” became a buffer, just like a traditional meeting The speech list; the real-time presentation of the co-written document adds to the rhythm of the dialogue.</p>

<p>Most importantly, this “semi-synchronized” discussion method allows participants to “tell the story” at their preferred rhythm. Youth issues are often related to their own experiences. Diverse expression methods not only allow more viewpoints to emerge, but also reduce the impact of oral expression ability, so that different life experiences can be equally reflected in meetings.</p>

<p>Because it was held online, we included not only the voices of young people in northern and southern Taiwan, but also a student from Berlin stayed up all night to participate in the whole process. The student remarked after the meeting: “You can share your personal experience with peace of mind, which is a kind of “de-edge”. I saw empathy in this discussion.”</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, En-en Hsu</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Open Government" /><category term="Youth Participation" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let different life experiences be equally reflected in the meeting.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/woman-gfe6d9bae1_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/woman-gfe6d9bae1_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Realizing the «Declaration for the Future of the Internet»</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%9C%AA%E4%BE%86%E7%B6%B2%E9%9A%9B%E7%B6%B2%E8%B7%AF%E5%AE%A3%E8%A8%80-%E5%A6%82%E4%BD%95%E5%AF%A6%E7%8F%BE/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Realizing the «Declaration for the Future of the Internet»" /><published>2022-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%9C%AA%E4%BE%86%E7%B6%B2%E9%9A%9B%E7%B6%B2%E8%B7%AF%E5%AE%A3%E8%A8%80-%E5%A6%82%E4%BD%95%E5%AF%A6%E7%8F%BE</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%9C%AA%E4%BE%86%E7%B6%B2%E9%9A%9B%E7%B6%B2%E8%B7%AF%E5%AE%A3%E8%A8%80-%E5%A6%82%E4%BD%95%E5%AF%A6%E7%8F%BE/"><![CDATA[<p>As the digital world readies for the golden age of web3, the opening line of “A Tale of Two Cities” by Charles Dickens rings more true today than at any time in the classic novel’s 160-year exisitence: “It was the best of times, it was the worst of times.”</p>

<p>Case in point is the Internet. It holds such a positon of importance that many compare it to the human body’s circulatory system. Experiences connected by hyperlinks transcending race, gender and status are instantly pumped around the world, enabling equal access to common resources and services. But this beautiful, essential life force is not without an all-too-real dark side.</p>

<p>User communities holding specific values easily find one another and form digital settlements following the convenience of transnational platforms. Studies show they soon engage in patterns of behavior intensifying confrontation and rivalry. The power asymmetry brought about by information centralization also leads to concerns of surveillance by the state and other government actors. At the same time, totalitarian regimes are taking the opportunity to redefine democratic freedom as “democracy under regulation” and “freedom within walls,” twisting the Internet into a stick that controls others and points at every corner.</p>

<p>This is essentially a Battle of Helm’s Deep between “digital totalitarianism” and “digital democracy”. As the global democratic camp strives to turn back the tide of centralization and polarization, passive is turned into active and a new model of governance created.</p>

<p>A bright and shining example involves pandemic management over the past two years. The “Mask Map” at the onset of COVID-19 centered on a government-released application programming interface (API) providing real-time stock information at pharmacies. Complementary measures included g0v civic technology community using the open API of the National Health Insurance Administration to create hundreds of applications. This cutting-edge approach relieved people’s anxiety and facilitated a good cycle of “protecting Taiwan and helping the world.”</p>

<p>Similarly, the need to record contact information when entering and leaving public places enabled the “1922 SMS Contact Tracing” to be developed and deployed in the shortest time possible. This fast, installation-free design also emerged from the g0v community. Completing contact tracing registration was silky smooth and also took into account privacy – anyone can check whether they have been queried by contact tracing personnel in the past 28 days by entering a registered mobile phone number.</p>

<p>These changes were ushered in with a decisive start via the 318 Movement in 2014. The world saw firsthand a prototype of digital democracy: Effective, direct actions made under the auspices of professional guidance and augmented civic technology. After the movement achieved its initial aims, the Executive Yuan invited the civic community to set up various platforms allowing the public to participate directly and assume the role of a force for innovation in policymaking.</p>

<p>Since 2016, each ministry has set up an “open government liaison” as a window for interministerial cooperation and as a communication bridge between the public sector and the people. On “join.gov.tw”, the online participation platform for public policy, anyone can initiate a proposal. And as long as more than 5,000 users second a proposal, the Open Government Liaison will invite stakeholders to hold cross-sector collaborative meetings to discuss ways of incorporating ideas into government decision-making. In this way, even members of the younger generation without the right to vote have the opportunity to develop entirely new policies.</p>

<p>In addition to making policy suggestions, the private sector directly participates in co-creation. The Presidential Hackathon, which is an important vehicle for advancing digital public construction, has been held for five consecutive years. It has welcomed thousands of social entrepreneurs, civil servants and teams from dozens of countries, with each edition seeing five outstanding teams selected and awarded by the president upon conclusion of the event.</p>

<p>Taiwan’s experience has shown that digital democracy is not a castle in the sky, but rather a kingdom of heaven. The crucial point is that governments must trust the people to present ideas and express opinions on policy reform as part and pacel of daily life. The beauty is that any country can adopt the same approach, make the government decision-making process transparent and use collaborative tools to assist, so scattered public opinion can be transformed into a continuous cycle of People-Public-Private partnerships (PPPP).</p>

<p>What has been tried over the years in Taiwan is more than just a democratic experiment in a single country, but a common goal of global partners. In 2022, I signed the “Declaration for the Future of the Internet” with representatives of 60 countries, formally expanding PPPP as a shared value for democratic allies.</p>

<p>In the declaration, countries with similar ideas jointly pledge to promote the openness and interoperability of the digital economy in a pluralistic and inclusive way, and to use a multistakeholder governance approach to build the Internet into a resilient structure strengthening mutual trust and protections of freedon and human rights.</p>

<p>Simply put, the declaration emphasizes the multiparty connections of “networks,” as well as the distributed structure of the “Internet”, which is both decentralized and interdependent. It can be seen that the strategy for digital development is not to issue licenses or to supervise, but to construct a “democratic network” in the Internet to promote innovation based on shared values.</p>

<p>The DIGI⁺ program of the Executive Yuan over the past six years has exactly the same intent as the declaration. DIGI stands for Digitization, Innovation, Governance and Inclusion. It lays the foundation for digital development, and integrates the spirit of diversity and integration. Improving the quality of digital services, promoting information security resilience and industrial development, and meeting the challenges of cross-border data governance, DIGI also includes Taiwan’s 20 national languages as part of digital inclusion.</p>

<p>Starting this year, we formally proposed the vision for the next phase: “Plurality”. Just like the Internet, which is composed of diverse network topologies, communities of all sizes can set up unique spaces and initiate action agendas, eliminating the restrictions of venues and time, allowing multiple choices and solutions to coexist harmoniously in creating mutually suitable interactive formats.</p>

<p>As an extension of a diverse society, the various groups in the multiverse remain autonomous and interconnected. The soon-to-be-established Ministry of Digital Affairs, or moda, will also expand the multiverse by “co-creating” the common vision and “integrating” the feelings of all parties through resilience building and open thinking. There is no question the best of times can be experienced through Taiwan’s model of “inclusive co-creation.”</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sheau-Tyng Peng</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Open Government" /><category term="Social Innovation" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[With democratic resilience and open innovation, we will usher in the best of times.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/234696ec-cdbf-4eff-9bbf-a5317e872169.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/234696ec-cdbf-4eff-9bbf-a5317e872169.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">“How” to open is important</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%A6%82%E4%BD%95-%E9%96%8B%E6%94%BE%E6%89%8D%E9%87%8D%E8%A6%81/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“How” to open is important" /><published>2022-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E3%80%8C%E5%A6%82%E4%BD%95%E3%80%8D%E9%96%8B%E6%94%BE%E6%89%8D%E9%87%8D%E8%A6%81</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%A6%82%E4%BD%95-%E9%96%8B%E6%94%BE%E6%89%8D%E9%87%8D%E8%A6%81/"><![CDATA[<p>Taiwan is surrounded by the sea on all sides, with rich streams and ponds. Every summer in recent years, SUP stand-up paddles, canoes and other activities are popular, adding colorful colors to the water surface.</p>

<p>This year, there are just two open government collaboration conferences with similar themes. The same proposer, Mr. Li Yuanzhi, made a request on the public policy online participation platform: “Please ask the Executive Yuan to review the open park waters, reservoirs, fishing ports and other public facilities. facilities, encourage the whole people to enjoy water and carry out water safety education, and comprehensively improve the water quality of the Chinese people.”</p>

<p>After the first stage of discussion, at the end of May, we invited stakeholders to collaborate online in different fields named by the proposers to jointly Explore how to open and apply.</p>

<p>Friends who love water activities hope that the government will implement the policy of lifting the ban on mountains and seas, and open up more “free” spaces for people to go into the water, so as to create a water-friendly environment for all.</p>

<p>The management unit does not shy away from saying that most people do not yet have the concept of taking their own risks. Therefore, being responsible for the “safety” of the people is still the top priority of the public sector, and even a burden.</p>

<p>The collaborative meeting allows government units to listen to public opinion, and at the same time allows the public to understand the division of powers and responsibilities and operations of government departments.</p>

<p>For example, the parks and lakes in the city are not managed by the special central regulations, but are regulated by the autonomous regulations of the counties and cities, which must be passed by the parliament. The management unit of the reservoir, in addition to the Water Resources Administration of the Ministry of Economic Affairs, also includes the Agricultural Committee, Taiwan Sugar, Taipower and other outsourced operators. As for fishing ports, there are differences between the first category, which is under the responsibility of the Central Fisheries Administration, and the second category, which is managed by counties and cities. Different powers and responsibilities can coordinate and cooperate, but they cannot act in their place.</p>

<p>A member of the public asked anxiously after listening to the briefing of the meeting: “This is to tell us that the waters in the park are useless to the Ministry of the Interior. Do we have to talk to the county and city governments one by one?”</p>

<p>” Yes.” We explain: This is not to shirk the blame, but to acknowledge the authority and effectiveness, as long as it is within the scope of the duties of the participating unit, you should know everything and strive to improve.</p>

<p>We hope to bring the ideological debate of “freedom” and “security” into a dialogue on “how to open and manage” in different fields. Therefore, the design allows the front-line colleagues of the aforementioned management units to discuss with the public one by one: open objects (people), processes (events), seasons (time), scope (place), and equipment (things). After all, a collaborative meeting is positioned as a cross-departmental communication platform. Focusing on issues and seeking truth from facts is a responsible approach.</p>

<p>The people and government units who participated on that day understood that they needed cooperation rather than confrontation, to provide assistance and tolerance to the masses who were not yet fully able to take their own recreational risks.</p>

<p>This meeting once again reflects the diverse appearances of the people. Some people want the government to leave it alone, while others ask the government to control more. The government is also three-dimensional. The central and local governments have equal rights. The path of centralization. Perhaps, this also coincides with the idea of open water advocates.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Yi-Wen Chan</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Open Government" /><category term="Collaborative Meeting" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Being able to focus on issues and be realistic is the responsible approach.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/beach-2836300_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/beach-2836300_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ocean State, Open Water</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%B5%B7%E6%B4%8B%E5%9C%8B%E5%AE%B6-%E9%96%8B%E6%94%BE%E6%B0%B4%E5%9F%9F/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ocean State, Open Water" /><published>2022-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%B5%B7%E6%B4%8B%E5%9C%8B%E5%AE%B6,%E9%96%8B%E6%94%BE%E6%B0%B4%E5%9F%9F</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E6%B5%B7%E6%B4%8B%E5%9C%8B%E5%AE%B6-%E9%96%8B%E6%94%BE%E6%B0%B4%E5%9F%9F/"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, the Join platform has two co-signatures on open water issues, which have been voted and passed, and a collaboration meeting will be held. Both proposals were proposed by Mr. Li Yuanzhi of the Taiwan Open Water Alliance. In April 2022, “<a href="https://join.gov.tw/idea/detail/87629654-2f3f-4660-9d2e-1321abcfef52">Articles 36 and 60 of the Development and Tourism Regulations were repealed, and real open water recreational activities</a>” and in june 2022 “<a href="https://join.gov.tw/idea/detail/9a4e5d11-e7c6-45ef-8510-b7c8f35d064a">please review the opening of public facilities such as park waters, reservoirs, fishing ports, encourage all people to enjoy water and conduct water safety education, and comprehensively improve the water quality for citizens</a>” was held to discuss not only the policy aspect, but also the actual implementation aspect of each water area.</p>

<p><a href="https://cm.pdis.nat.gov.tw/111/">The first collaboration meeting</a> was held at the Yilan Waiao Visitor Center. We invited multiple stakeholders, including relevant industry players and players. , scholars and experts, and management parties such as the National Park Management Office, the National Scenic Area Management Office, the Yilan County Government, the New Taipei City Government, and the Kaohsiung City Government, so that everyone from the central and local governments can communicate and discuss at the same table. Participating people raised questions and feelings to the management unit on the spot, and the Tourism Bureau of the Ministry of Communications also expressed the position of “open principle and exception management”, hoping that individual management units can improve the current restrictions on the use of the public. We took stock of the needs of all parties at the end of the meeting, discussed possible solutions and dilemmas, and in the process of collaboration, let the open waters move forward little by little.</p>

<p><a href="https://cm.pdis.nat.gov.tw/118/">Second Collaboration Meeting</a> Due to the epidemic, it will be handled online. People hope that parks, reservoirs and fishing ports can be opened for use, but they also find that the competent authorities in these three places are different. For example, parks are regulated by local self-government regulations, while reservoirs may be under the jurisdiction of the Water Resources Department, the Agriculture Committee, Taiwan Sugar, and Taipower; the fishing ports are divided into the central fishery department or managed by local counties and cities, and all need to participate in the discussion. Because of the diverse geographical characteristics of reservoirs, we also took inventory of aerial photos and discussed multiple reservoirs on a case-by-case basis.</p>

<p>The public has been actively discussing issues related to open water, so the two collaborative meetings were broadcast live, and the Pol.is digital tool was used to analyze public opinion before the meeting. The public demand for management also examines the distribution of powers and responsibilities between the central and local governments. We hope that through open government collaboration meetings, players and management units can go from “opposition” to “dialogue” to find a way to balance “freedom” and “safety”, and continue to communicate through multiple ministries and local governments. Improve open waters shared by all.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sean Chou</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Open Government" /><category term="Collaborative Meeting" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let's go to the water and the sea together!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://image.cache.storm.mg/styles/smg-800x533-fp/s3/media/image/2022/07/04/20220704-023639_U1004_M774171_8803.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://image.cache.storm.mg/styles/smg-800x533-fp/s3/media/image/2022/07/04/20220704-023639_U1004_M774171_8803.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">All aboard the SBTs express</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/Web3-%E7%9A%84%E9%9D%88%E9%AD%82-SBT-%E6%86%91%E8%AD%89/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="All aboard the SBTs express" /><published>2022-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/Web3-%E7%9A%84%E9%9D%88%E9%AD%82-SBT-%E6%86%91%E8%AD%89</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/Web3-%E7%9A%84%E9%9D%88%E9%AD%82-SBT-%E6%86%91%E8%AD%89/"><![CDATA[<p>What exactly are “soulbound tokens” (SBTs)? This new concept, stemming from non-fungible tokens (NFTs), is poised to change the web3 world. In <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jp1L-DGYnJA">my recent #InnoMinds video podcast</a>, Ethereum co-founder Vitalik Buterin shared his thoughts on digital communities and free speech. He also <a href="https://youtu.be/jp1L-DGYnJA?t=2389">elaborated on SBTs</a>, the core of the paper <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4105763">Decentralized Society: Finding Web3’s Soul (DeSoc)</a>, which he co-authored with RadicalxChange founder Glen Weyl and Flashbots’ Strategist Puja Ohlhaver this past May.</p>

<p>The term “soulbound,” proposed by Vitalik earlier this year, was inspired by the online game World of Warcraft. In the game, certain items with special powers (such as a sword) cannot be transferred or sold to others once they have been collected by a player. This is a “soulbound item,” and the benefit of “soul binding” is that it avoids speculation on the item while increasing participation. Players cannot obtain such items while hiding; they must make full use of “soulbound items” to face genuine challenges and tasks.</p>

<p>Games offer rich metaphors for the journey of life. While earning swords offer a player advantage, “winning” requires larger coordination among a larger group, such as a “guild,” where the sum is greater than the parts. Can the web3 world, which has only recently emerged, follow the same rules? As the authors note, “soul-bound tokens” are also “community-bound tokens,” as they represent participation in groups. </p>

<p>In the recent past, speculative, wholly transferable virtual assets unmoored to community coordination (such as various “coins” and NFTs) have been the focus of attention. However, transactions based solely on anonymity and unilateral transferability is essentially a cynical conduit for human greed. Rug-pulling, vampire attacks, sybil-attacked “airdrops”, and phishing scams are some of the most notorious examples. </p>

<p>Solutions to these problems are floated in Vitalik and his co-authors’ paper. One idea is that a “soul” is a pseudonymous account tied to a person or entity and that SBTs are the badges collected in the account. These badges represent non-transferable memberships to communities. In other words, once you mint an SBT, you cannot give it to others. </p>

<p>Communities can also issue SBTs to each other. For example, the <a href="https://clab.org.tw/en/architecture/social-innovation-lab/">Social Innovation Lab</a> in Taipei City can be a “soul” distributing SBTs to various resident organizations. Likewise, a university can distribute SBTs to its affiliated schools. Through giving and receiving in various social relationships, SBTs act as mutual authentications. As a result of their ongoing public interactions, parties increase authenticity and mutual trust.</p>

<p>Many online games offer not just swords which you can unilaterally wield, but also voting rights on how to steward your guild’s gold. Similarly, “souls” accumulate SBTs that reflect their solidarities and rights to participate. While such social advantages may become the source of inequities, SBTs allow participants to see and thus adjust for such advantages, encouraging social diversity and cooperation across these differences.</p>

<p>What if you lose your account, or it’s hijacked? It’s easy to recover SBTs by asking the issuers to revoke and reissue. The authors also propose more sophisticated security mechanisms like “community recovery,” where you can ask a diverse set of connections represented in your SBT communities to recover your account together. </p>

<p>After the #InnoMinds dialogue with Vitalik, I believe two avenues are open. First, SBTs have the potential to supplement the shortcomings of cross-border public participation. Case in point: No universal authentication mechanism exists for those wishing to take part in civic affairs remotely. Why? Because the individual has never been to said country and does not have a local mobile phone number, visa, or identity certificate. SBTs can bridge the authentication gap in such cases by leveraging shared community bonds.</p>

<p>Moreover, while identity authentication is done on an individual basis worldwide, SBTs view communities as first-class citizens. This approach alleviates “headcount competition” in decision-making. It reminds me of Pol.is, a popular tool in Taiwan for gathering opinions, which also treats individuals with closely related preferences as a community. Anyone wishing to place an issue on the agenda must persuade all other communities, in direct contrast to the 51%-takes-all approach.</p>

<p>It goes without saying that I am pleased to see SBTs following suit by rewarding collaboration across diverse communities and building intersectional identities from overlapping groups. In this way, we can ensure truly inclusive co-creation, even for large-scale referendums. This is critical in guaranteeing that the voices of all are heard clearly and fairly.</p>

<p>The concept of SBTs shows how innovative mechanisms in civic technology can create new avenues for democracy. I look forward to experimenting with more communities and finding out how they wish to implement SBTs, with an eye toward Plurality—a decentralized society in which all souls are treasured, and displaced people are sheltered.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Sheau-Tyng Peng</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Social Innovation" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The “soulbound tokens” is poised to change the web3 world.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn-cw-english.cwg.tw/article/202206/article-62ba90a0b8fa0.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn-cw-english.cwg.tw/article/202206/article-62ba90a0b8fa0.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Finding the intersection of opposites</title><link href="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%B0%8B%E6%89%BE%E5%B0%8D%E7%AB%8B%E4%B8%AD%E7%9A%84%E4%BA%A4%E9%9B%86/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Finding the intersection of opposites" /><published>2022-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%B0%8B%E6%89%BE%E5%B0%8D%E7%AB%8B%E4%B8%AD%E7%9A%84%E4%BA%A4%E9%9B%86</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/blog/%E5%B0%8B%E6%89%BE%E5%B0%8D%E7%AB%8B%E4%B8%AD%E7%9A%84%E4%BA%A4%E9%9B%86/"><![CDATA[<p>Since the outbreak of the epidemic, the shortage of medical care manpower has intensified the conflicts between caregivers and care recipients for many years. “Severely punish 50,000 escaped foreign workers, shorten the care window period caused by escape, include family care in the Ministry of Health and Welfare, and protect the right to care and human rights of the disabled and demented” <a href="https://join.gov .tw/idea/detail/285f0a1c-eaf3-408c-8d29-7225573921d5">joint case</a> was initiated by netizens, and after 5,000 signatures, it was selected as the [collaboration meeting] in our office (https://cm.pdis.nat.gov. tw/109/) theme. The collaborative process of opening up the government requires listening to the opinions of all parties and acting as a bridge of communication, which is especially difficult in long-term conflicting issues. We are working closely with the Ministry of Labour this time on this difficult task.</p>

<p>The content of this proposal involves many Chinese policies that have already been implemented, and the Ministry of Labor needs to carefully assist the public in clarifying the facts. In the collaborative meeting, we use the <a href="https://miro.com/app/board/uxjvost2l2c=/?share_link_id=505761772493">Mind Map</a> to organize the data collected in advance and summarize the discussions on the spot in real time. The representative of the proposal shared with us after the meeting: “I have learned about the working of collaborative meetings before, and many of the participants participated in this way for the first time, including slideo and mind maps. This time, everyone’s imagination was concreted. , I think this kind of meeting process is very good, and I hope to continue to follow up and let the participants know more information.”</p>

<p>Another feature of the collaborative meeting is that all parties can share their experiences and difficulties face-to-face and communicate with each other. understand. “The needs of employers, labor unions and agents are different. Originally, everyone opposed and imagined each other, but when you come to the scene, you will see that every need is real, and you can listen to the real situation of others.” The representative of the proposal said this .</p>

<p>The desk leader who led the group discussion to facilitate such a discussion is absolutely indispensable. Each collaborative meeting was led by open government liaisons from different ministries. This time we invited Ruchen from the Financial Services Council, Yi Shan from the Ministry of Economic Affairs, and Yin Zhe from the Mainland Affairs Council. Yishan shared her tips for leading this discussion: “If there are people in the group who want to immediately refute other people’s speech, I encourage them to write it down first, and the situation will improve.” Yishan also added: “Emphasis more on giving everyone completeness. The speaking time.” Some participants also shared the live discussion: “The second group of Confucian ministers and section chiefs brought them very well. They can change conflicting words and leave them to the next person to speak.” During the discussion, it was inevitable to participate in Mixed emotions, it is necessary to rely on clear thoughts, the small desk leader organizes the words, and finds the right person to respond to the question and promote the discussion.</p>

<p>Of course, a collaborative meeting alone cannot completely resolve a long-standing conflict. However, through such sorting and discussion, we can find a direction that everyone can agree on, and then we can continue to advance. A participant said to us: “It is surprising that a basic consensus can be reached under such conflicts. Although the consensus is not deep in a limited time, it can be a little bit in the original situation of opposition. It is not easy to meet each other.”</p>

<p>We hope that this kind of discussion will be a starting point, and through the arrangement of data, complete records, and face-to-face communication and sharing of experience, we will build a bridge between the government and the people. To formulate policies, we no longer rely solely on the unilateral conception and implementation of the government, but through the power of the people to find the intersection of opposites, so as to ensure the direction of policy implementation and meet the needs of all parties.</p>]]></content><author><name>Audrey Tang, Hao-Ting Chang</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Open Government" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every need is real, and you can listen to the real situation of others.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/hospice-gc4866b1b9_1280.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pdis.nat.gov.tw/en/assets/imgs/hospice-gc4866b1b9_1280.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>